[
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Who wrote the title page of The Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Mormon",
    "options": ["Joseph Smith", "Mormon", "Moroni"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The abridgment of the record is written to the Jew and Gentile.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The record is written by way of commandment, and also by the spirit of ____ and of revelation.",
    "answer": "prophecy"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The record was written and sealed up, and hid up unto the Lord, that they may not be destroyed",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Where in the Book of Mormon is the word Lamanites first mentioned?",
    "answer": "Title Page"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The word “Jaredites” first appears to in the Title page of the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "An abridgment is taken from the Book of ____, which is a record of the people of Jared.",
    "answer": "ether"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The people of Jared were scattered at the time the Lord confounded their language.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "At time the Lord confounded the language of the Jaredites, they were trying to build a ____ to get to heaven.",
    "answer": "tower"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord has done many great things unto the remnant of the House of ____.",
    "answer": "Israel"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord wants to show the remnant House of Israel the many great things that he has done for their fathers.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord wants the House of Israel to know the ____ he has made with them and not be cast-off forever.",
    "answer": "Covenants",
    "options": ["Bible", "Articles of Faith", "Covenants"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "The Lord wants to convince Jews and Gentiles that Jesus is the ____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Jesus is the Christ, the Eternal God, manifesting himself unto all nations.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Mormon states that if there are faults in the record, they are the ____ of Men.",
    "answer": "Mistakes"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Mormon writes, condemn not the things of God?",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Mormon wants us to be found spotless at the _____ seat of Christ",
    "answer": "Judgment"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Mormon Title Page",
    "question": "Who translated the title page of the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Joseph Smith",
    "options": ["Moroni", "Mormon", "Joseph Smith"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "In the brief analysis of the Book of Mormon we are told that there are namely three classes of record plates.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "The Brass Plates of Laban are mentioned frequently in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "The body of the Book of Mormon, from Mosiah to Mormon, chapter #7, inclusive, is the translation of whose ____ abridgment of the Plates of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Mormon"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "The period covered in the Book of Mormon extends from B.C. 600 to A.D. 421.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "Who was the last of the Nephite historians?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "Moroni was the last of the Nephite historians that sealed the sacred record, and hid up unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Brief Analysis",
    "question": "In the Brief Analysis of the Book of Mormon, Joseph Smith mentions the hill Cumorah by name.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Ether 15:11",
    "question": "The hill Cumorah was referred as the hill Ramah by the Jaredites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Mor 1:3, 4:23",
    "question": "The hill Cumorah was referred as the hill Shim by the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Look! @ BOM",
    "question": "In what beautiful state, is the hill Cumorah located.",
    "answer": "New York"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "On the night of September 21, 1823, who appeared to Joseph Smith Junior ____?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "When Moroni first appeared to Joseph Smith he referred to him as a personage.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "When Joseph sought the Lord in fervent prayer, he discovered a_____ appearing in his room.",
    "answer": "light"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The light that appeared to Joseph, was lighter than noon-day.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The personage that appeared to Joseph Smith was ____, and he was standing in the air.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "When Moroni appeared to Joseph Smith, he was standing in the air.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni’s robe was of the most exquisite ____.",
    "answer": "whiteness",
    "options": ["Color", "Whiteness", "Design"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph Smith writes: That he believed that anything earthly could be made to appear so exceedingly white or brilliant.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph Smith said that he could see Moroni’s hands were naked and his arms also, a little above the wrists.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni’s ____ and neck were also bare, when he appeared to Joseph Smith.",
    "answer": "Head"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph Smith could see that Moroni was wearing clothing that is worn by worthy temple workers.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Because Moroni’s head and neck were bare, Joseph Smith could see into Moroni’s ____.",
    "answer": "bosom"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Not only was Moroni’s robe exceedingly white, his whole person was glorious beyond description.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph Smith states that ____ countenance was truly like lightning.",
    "answer": "moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni’s countenance was truly like lightning, when he appeared to Joseph Smith.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The light that surrounded ____ was brighter than the light of the room.",
    "answer": "moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "When Joseph Smith first saw Moroni, he was afraid.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Who was afraid of Moroni, when he first appeared in his room?",
    "answer": "Joseph Smith"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "It took a very long time for Joseph Smith to get over of being afraid of Moroni.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "At first, Joseph Smith was afraid of Moroni, but soon the ____ left him.",
    "answer": "Fear",
    "options": ["Fear", "Sadness", "Glory"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The messenger called Joseph Smith by name.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph Smith, that his name would be had for good and ____.",
    "answer": "evil"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The messenger to Joseph that all nation’s, kindreds, and ____, would speak evil of his name.",
    "answer": "tongues"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The messenger to Joseph that all nation’s, kindreds, and tongues would speak evil of his name.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni said that there was a_____ deposited in the ground, written upon gold plates.",
    "answer": "Book",
    "options": ["Manuscript", "Book", "Tablet"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The book that was deposited in the ground was written on what type of metal?",
    "answer": "Gold",
    "options": ["Silver", "Brass", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The book gave an account of the former ____ of the continent.",
    "answer": "Inhabitants",
    "options": ["Inhabitants", "Dinosaurs", "Birds"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Ask someone that knows",
    "question": "What is the name of continent in which the book was deposited and in which we in the united states live?",
    "answer": "North America"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The book gives an account of the former inhabitants of this continent, and the source from whence they sprang.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The ____ of the everlasting Gospel was contained in the book; that was deposited in the earth.",
    "answer": "fulness"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The fulness of the everlasting Gospel is contained in the Book.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The fulness of the everlasting Gospel was delivered by the ____, to the former ancient inhabitants.",
    "answer": ["savior", "lord"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "What shade of color were the two stones in the bow?",
    "answer": "Silver",
    "options": ["Metallic", "Gold", "Silver"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The two stones in silver bows were fastened to a breastplate.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Another name that is given to the two stones and breastplate is the ____.",
    "answer": "Urim and Thummim"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The Urim and Thummim is what constitutes the two stones and the breastplate.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "No ref because they are not.",
    "question": "The Urim and Thummim are mentioned by name in the text of Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The possession and the use of these stones were what constituted what word?",
    "answer": "Seers"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The Seers were not used in ancientformer times.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The Seers were madeprepared by whom?",
    "answer": ["god", "lord"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The Seers were prepared by God; for the purpose of translating the book, of which is now known as the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "With the possession and use of the Seers, people cancould translate ancient writings.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Angel Moroni told Joseph Smith to show the plates to anyone that he pleased.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph was told not to show the plates to anyone, unless he was ____ to do so.",
    "answer": "Commanded"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph was commanded by Moroni, to show only the breastplate and not the Urim and Thummim.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Unless Joseph was commanded; Moroni said that he must not show the plates and Urim and Thummin to anyonehe would be destroyed.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "While Joseph was conversing with Moroni about the plates, he had a ____.",
    "answer": "Vision",
    "options": ["Vision", "Seizure", "Migraine Headache"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "In his vision, Joseph Smith could see the place where the plates were deposited.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The vision was so clear and distinct, that Joseph knew where the place was when he visited it.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "After the communication, Joseph saw the light in the room begin to gather around this person.",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Except around Moroni, the room began to get dark again.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "A conduit opened right up into ____, and Moroni ascended until he entirely disappeared.",
    "answer": "heaven"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph states and refers to the light in his room as being heavenly.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "After the messenger and the light left, Joseph fell asleep.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph lay in bed and was overwhelmed with astonishment at what he had both ____, and heard.",
    "answer": "seen"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The second time the messenger appeared to Joseph, he repeated the same words as the first time, without variation.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph ____ would try to tempt him.",
    "answer": "satan"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni informed Joseph of great judgments which were coming upon the ____.",
    "answer": "Earth",
    "options": ["People", "Heavens", "Earth"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni said that great judgments were coming upon the earth such as; desolations by famine, sword, and ____.",
    "answer": "Pestilence"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "At what time did Moroni say that the judgements were coming to the earth?",
    "answer": "This generation",
    "options": ["Noah's time", "This generation", "The generation to come"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph writes that he and his father’s family were indigent.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph that he must have no other object in view in getting the plates but glorify ____.",
    "answer": "god"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph Smith that he must not be influenced by any other motive than that of building the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "How many times did the angel Moroni visit Joseph Smith in one single night?",
    "answer": "Three",
    "options": ["One", "Two", "Three"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Angel Moroni visited Joseph Smith three times in September of 1823.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "After Moroni’s third visit, as he ascended into heaven; What kind of fowl did Joseph hear crowed.",
    "answer": "Rooster",
    "options": ["Swan", "Rooster", "Turkey"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni left, and Joseph realized that their interviews must of have taken all night because the day had approach.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph attempted to work as other times, but found that his strength was ____.",
    "answer": "Exhausted",
    "options": ["Exhausted", "Gone", "Stronger"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Because of his exhausted strength, Joseph’s father told him to go home.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "While attempting to cross the _____ out of the field, Joseph's strength left him and he fell to the ground.",
    "answer": "Fence",
    "options": ["River", "Highway", "Fence"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph fell to the ground and was unconscious for three days.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "In the Origin of the Book of Mormon: It does not sayhow long Joseph exactly lay unconscious.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Who appeared to Joseph Smith when he arose from his unconsciousness?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph was ____ by Moroni to tell his father, of the vision and commandments he had received.",
    "answer": "Commanded",
    "options": ["Told", "Exhorted", "Commanded"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph obeyed Moroni, and returned to his father in the field, and rehearsed the whole matter to him.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph left out some important details, when he rehearsed the story to his father.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph’s father told him to go to the place where the Messenger had told him to go.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph new the place where the plates were deposited because of the dream that he had.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Because of his_____, Joseph knew the place where the plates were buried.",
    "answer": "Vision",
    "options": ["Hindsight", "Vision", "Foresight"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The hill where the plates were deposited was more elevated than the other surrounding hills.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Convenient to what village is the Hill Cumorah located?",
    "answer": "Manchester"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "What person is represented by statue, atop the Hill Cumorah?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph Smith tells us the plates were hidden under a considerable size stone and facing what direction?",
    "answer": "West",
    "options": ["North", "South", "West"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "When Joseph Smith removed the earth that was fixed under the stone, he had a difficult time.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "When Joseph Smith looked into the stone box; it contained the plates, the ____, and the breastplate.",
    "answer": "Urim and Thummim"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph Smith made an attempt to get the things out of the box, but was forbidden by whom?",
    "answer": ["messanger", "moroni"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph Smith that the time had not come yet to get the things out of the box.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "How many years would pass before Joseph Smith could get the things out of the box?",
    "answer": "Four",
    "options": ["Two", "Three", "Four"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Moroni told Joseph Smith to come precisely one year from the time that he first saw him and that he would meet with him again.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph Smith did as he was ____, and he went at the end of each year and at each time, he found the same messenger there waiting for him.",
    "answer": "Commanded",
    "options": ["Forbidden", "Commanded", "Instructed"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph Smith received instructions and ____, from the messenger, at each of their interviews.",
    "answer": "Intelligence",
    "options": ["Gold", "Money", "Intelligence"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph what the Lord was going to do, and how and what manner His kingdom was to be conducted in the last days.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The messenger delivered the plates to Joseph and told him that he was to be responsible for them and if he would let them go carelessly, he would not be cut off.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The messenger told Joseph that he should use all of his endeavors to preserve the ____.",
    "answer": "Plates",
    "options": ["Hill Cumorah", "Plates", "House of his Father"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph Smith was told by the messenger what would be required of him to do by his hand.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph was told by the messenger: That the ____ would be protected until he should call for them again.",
    "answer": "Plates"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "As soon as it was found out that he had the plates, multitudes of people were out to get them away from them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Who do you think told people that Joseph Smith had a book written upon gold plates?",
    "answer": ["adversary", "satan"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "Joseph Smith said that every_____ that could be invented was resorted to take away the plates from him.",
    "answer": "Stratagem",
    "options": ["Stratagem", "Device", "Intelligence"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "When the messenger called for the plates, Joseph Smith did not deliver them unto him until he was commanded.",
    "answer": "F"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "According to Joseph Smith, Who has the platesis in charge of them to this day?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon was translated into modern speech by the gift and power of_____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "As attested by Divine affirmation, the ancient record has been brought forth from the earth.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to Origin of BOM",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon was first published to the world in what year of our Lord?",
    "answer": "1830",
    "options": ["1821", "1823", "1830"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Look! @ BOM",
    "question": "What is the name of the artist who painted most of the Book of Mormon paintings?",
    "answer": ["Arnold", "Friberg"]
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "ref": "Refer to the Testimony of Three Witnesses in the BOM",
    "question": "Who were the Three Witnesses of the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer and Martin Harris",
    "options": [
      "Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer and Lorenzo Snow",
      "Joseph Smith Sr, Brigham Young and Nephi",
      "Oliver Cowdery, David Whitmer and Martin Harris"
    ]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to the Testimony of the Eight Witnesses in the BOM",
    "question": "In the testimony of the Eight Witnesses, they describe the plates of having the appearance of ancient work, and of curious workmanship.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Refer to the Testimony of the Eight Witnesses in the BOM",
    "question": "In the testimony of the Eight Witnesses, they state that they gave their names to the world, to witness unto the world that, that they handled the plates with their hands and saw the engraving thereon.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to the Testimony of the Eight Witnesses in the BOM",
    "question": "The Eight Witnesses state that they “lie not” and bear witness unto whom?",
    "answer": "god"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to BOM",
    "question": "What is the title of the first book in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to BOM",
    "question": "What is the title of the last book in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Moroni"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The longest book in the Book of Mormon is the Book of Mosiah?",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "Refer to BOM"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "What is the longest book in the Book of Mormon",
    "answer": "Alma",
    "ref": "Refer to BOM"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon book has the least verses",
    "answer": "Jarom",
    "ref": "Refer to BOM"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "What is the name of the book that has the second least amount of verses",
    "answer": "The Words Of Mormon",
    "ref": "Refer to BOM"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The words: “was the son of “are used how many times in the Book of Ether.",
    "options": [15, 20, 21],
    "answer": "21",
    "ref": "Refer to BOM"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Omni",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon author wrote the least amount of words in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Chemish"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to Book of Omni",
    "question": "This Book of Mormon author only wrote one verse.",
    "answer": "Chemish"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:4",
    "question": "A prophet would the Lord God raise up among the Jews-even a _____, or, in other words, a Savior of the world.",
    "answer": "Messiah"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "There are only three women mentioned by name in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "Abish-Alma19:16, Eve-1Nep5:11, Isabel-Alma39:3, Mary-Mos3:8, Sariah-1Nep2:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi was born of _____ parents.",
    "options": [" bad", " naughty", " goodly"],
    "answer": "goodly",
    "ref": "1Nep:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was taught somewhat in all the learning of his father.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi saw many_____ in the course of his days.",
    "options": ["bad things", "afflictions", "parties"],
    "answer": "afflictions",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13, Alma 12:221, 42:2-3",
    "question": "What modern day weapon has been around since the beginning of man?",
    "answer": "Sword"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was highly favored of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "What Book of Mormon historian was highly favored of the Lord?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many days was, Nephi highly favored of the Lord?  c-(B)",
    "options": ["half", "all", "neither half nor all"],
    "answer": "all",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1",
    "question": "Nephi had_____ knowledge of the goodness and the mysteries of God.",
    "answer": "Great"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was not a very smart prophet.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said: “I make a record of my proceedings in my days”.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Refer to BOM",
    "question": "The record that Nephi made about his reign and ministry is known to us as the: “First Book Of _____”.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:2",
    "question": "Nephi made a record in the _____ of his father.",
    "answer": "Language"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi’s writing’s consists of the learning of what tribe of people?",
    "options": ["Jews", "Egyptians", "Mongols"],
    "answer": "Jews",
    "ref": "1Nep1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi was taught by his father in the language of the _____",
    "options": ["Israelites", "Egyptians", "Mongols"],
    "answer": "Egyptians",
    "ref": "1Nep1:2 & Mosiah1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi taught Lehi the language of the Egyptians.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that his record is somewhat true as far as he can remember.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",

    "question": "Nephi wrote that: The record which I make is true; and I make it with mine own hand”.",

    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi made the record according to his_____.  (a) -(C)",
    "options": ["memory", "will", "knowledge"],
    "answer": "knowledge",
    "ref": "1Nep1:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "It came to pass in the commencement of the_____ year of the reign Zedekiah. ",
    "options": ["1st", "2nd", "3rd"],
    "answer": "1st",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "Who was the king of Judah at the time that Nephi wrote the book of Nephi?",
    "answer": "Zedekiah"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What body of land did king Zedekiah reign over.",
    "options": ["Egypt", "Israel", "Judah"],
    "answer": "Judah",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "What important city was located in the land of Judah?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In the beginning of the Book of Nephi: He writes that Lehi lived in Jerusalem all his days.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",

    "question": "Lehi was Nephi's uncle.",

    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",

    "question": "Lehi was the father of Nephi.",

    "answert": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What kind of people came to Jerusalem at the same year of the commencement of the reign of King Zedekiah?  (a) Jews (b) prophets(c) Hebrews (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Many prophets came to the city of Jerusalem and prophesied that if the people did not repent, the city would be destroyed.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4",
    "question": "What city in the land of Judah would be destroyed if the people did not repent?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The city of Jerusalem; was a great city according to Nephi.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi prayed on behalf of his_____.  (a) wives (b) pets(c) people-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:5",
    "question": "Who did Lehi pray to and asked that the city would not be destroyed?",
    "answer": ["god", "lord"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi prayed to the Lord with all his heart.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6",
    "question": "As Lehi prayed unto the Lord, there came a pillar of_____.",
    "answer": "Fire"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When Lehi was praying unto the Lord, a pillar of fire appeared.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The pillar of fire did not dwell upon a rock; instead it flew over Lehi’s head.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the pillar of fire, Lehi saw and heard much.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Because of the things Lehi saw and heard he did quake and_____ exceedingly.  (a) danced the Macarena (b) did the twist(c) tremble-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi cast himself upon his bed, being overcome by the_____.  (a) heat (b) Spirit(c) devil-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi cast himself to bed because he was overcome by the Spirit.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "And being thus overcome with the Spirit, Lehi was carried away in a_____.",
    "answer": "Vision"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi saw in his vision the_____ opened.  (a) earth (b) heavens(c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "In his vision, who did Lehi see sitting upon his throne?",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "Lehi saw God sitting upon his_____.",
    "answer": "Throne"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In his vision Lehi saw the Devil being cast out of heaven.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "_____was sitting upon his throne, surrounded with numberless concourses of angels.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "God sat on his throne, and was surrounded by one million angels.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "As God sat on his throne, angels were singing and praising their God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:8",
    "question": "In his vision, Lehi saw____ singing and praising their God.",
    "answer": "Angels"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9",
    "question": "Lehi saw one/person descending out of the midst of_____.",
    "answer": "Heaven"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The person’s luster that Lehi saw descending out of heaven was above that of the sun at noon-day.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The word “noon-day” only appears once in the text of the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many times does the word “noon-day” appear in the text of the Book of Mormon? (a) 1 (b) 2(c) 3-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:9"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many persons followed the first person that Lehi saw in his vision? (a) 3 (b) six(c) 12-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Twelve others followed the first person that Lehi saw in his vision.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The brightness of the twelve people that Lehi saw in his vision exceeded that of the stars in the firmament.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Whose brightness exceeded that of the stars in the firmament? (a) the devil (b) the twelve(c) Laman’s-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The first person that Lehi saw descending out of heaven and the twelve others that followed him; came down and went forth upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11",
    "question": "All the people that Lehi saw descending out of heaven came down and went forth upon the face of the_____.",
    "answer": "Earth"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What person stood before Lehi and gave him a book and bade him to read it. (a) 1st person (b) 2nd person(c) the 3rd –(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi choose not to read the book that the first person gave him to read.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:12",
    "question": "When Lehi read the book that he was given; he was filled with the____ of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi did not pray before he read the book that he was given and consequently, did not feel the Spirit of the Lord.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:12"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "In the book that he was given Lehi saw the abominations of what city in the land of Judah?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "Lehi said: “Woe, woe, unto_____, for I have seen thine abominations!”",
    "answer": "Jereusalem"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi saw and read many things concerning the city of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi saw and read that the city of Jerusalem would be destroyed and also it's inhabitants.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Many of the people of Jerusalem would perish by the_____ and be carried away captive.  (a) knife (b) sword(c) famine-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Only those that were unrighteous would perish by the sword and be carried into captivity.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:13",
    "question": "Lehi saw the people of Jerusalem perish and be carried away captive to_____.",
    "answer": "Babylon"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi read and saw many_____ and marvelous things and exclaimed many things unto the Lord.  (a) bad (b) good(c) great-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi said “great and marvelous are thy works, O Lord God_____”(a) almighty (b) gosh darn it (c) its all good-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "According to Lehi, where is the throne of God located? (a) close to the moon (b) the heavens(c) underneath the stars-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said the throne of God is located in the heavens.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi said that God’s power, goodness, and mercy are over all the_____ of the earth. (a) people (b) inhabitants (c) unrighteous-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said that God is merciful.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi saw and read that God was not very merciful to the inhabitants of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:14",
    "question": "Because God is _____, he will not suffer those that come unto him to perish.",
    "answer": "Merciful"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi did not praise God because of the things he had seen.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the things Lehi saw his soul did rejoice.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:15",
    "question": "Lehi’s soul did rejoice, and his_____ was filled because of the things he saw.",
    "answer": "Heart"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi made a full account of the thing which his father wrote.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep1:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:16",
    "question": "Lehi wrote many things which he saw in visions and in_____.",
    "answer": "Dreams"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi said that Lehi had written many things which he prophesied and spoke unto his_____.  (a) daughters (b) uncles(c) children-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi made an account of his proceedings.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17",
    "question": "Who made an abridgement of the record of his father?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17",
    "question": "The plates that Nephi made for the record, were made by his_____.",
    "answer": "Hand"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi first made an abridgment of the record of Lehi then he made an account of his life.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi prophesied and declared to the people of Jerusalem the marvelous things which he had seen and heard.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19",
    "question": "The Jews did_____, Lehi because of the things he testified of them.",
    "answer": "Mock"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi testified to the Jews of things which he saw and heard, and also of the things which he read in a book.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19",
    "question": "The book which Lehi read; manifested plainly of the coming of the_____.",
    "answer": "Messiah"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Jews were angry with Lehi even as with the prophets of old.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20",
    "question": "Because of the things that he had said, the Jews sought to kill_____.",
    "answer": "Lehi"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20",
    "question": "The Jews: _____out, and stoned, and slain, the prophets of old in the city of Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "Cast"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that he would show unto us that the tender mercies of the Lord are over all those whom he hath chosen.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Because of their_____, the Lord will make those that he has chosen mighty even unto the power of deliverance.  (a) riches (b) pride(c) faith-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep1:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Jews were angry with Lehi because he testified of their wickedness and abominations.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep1:19-20"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord spoke to Lehi in a dream and told him he was blessed for things that he had done.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:1",
    "question": "Lehi was faithful and declared unto the people the things which the_____ had commanded him to say.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The people in Jerusalem sough to take away Lehi’s life.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:2",
    "question": "The ____ came to Lehi in a dream and commanded him to depart into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi did not obey the word of the Lord, and did not depart until he was ready.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:5",
    "question": "By what borders and shore of a sea did Lehi and his family travel to?",
    "answer": "Red Sea"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:5",
    "question": "What was Nephi’s mother’s name?",
    "answer": "Sariah"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many days did Lehi and his family travel before pitching their tents for the first time? (a) 2 (b) 3(c) 4 (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Lehi built an altar of_____.  (a) rocks (b) clay(c) stones-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi made an offering unto the Lord and gave thanks unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Which son die Lehi name a river after; that emptied into the Red Sea?  (a)  Nephi (b) Sam,(c) Laman- (C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The name of the river that emptied into the Red Sea was called_____.  (a) the snake, (b) the Mississippi,(c) Laman-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:8",
    "question": "Lehi named a river after one of his sons",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:9",
    "question": "Which one of his son’s was Lehi speaking to when he said” O that thou mightest be like unto this river, continually running into the fountain of all righteousness!",
    "answer": "Laman"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:10",
    "question": "Lehi was referring to Lemuel when he said “O that thou might be like unto this valley, firm and stead-fest, and immovable in keeping the commandments of the Lord!”",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi spoke encouraging words to Laman and Lemuel because of their_____.  (a) looks (b) stiffneckedness(c) clothes-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For behold Laman and Lemuel did murmur in many things against Lehi.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "question": "Lehi was a visionary man.",
    "answer": "t"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers murmured because Lehi had led them out of Jerusalem, to leave the land of their inheritance, and their gold and_____.",
    "answer": "Silver"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel left behind their precious things and thought they were going to perish in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers said that Lehi had led them into the wilderness because of the foolish imaginations of his_____.  (a) heart (b) head(c) mind-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:12",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel murmured because they did not know the dealings of that_____, who had created them.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel did not believe that what great city could be destroyed. (a) Salt Lake City, (b) Sugar City,(c) Jerusalem. (C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi’s two older brothers did not believe that Jerusalem could be destroyed according to the words of the_____.  (a) 3 wise men (b) prophets(c) holy men-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi writes that his older brothers were like the Jews who sought to take away the life of his father.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14",
    "question": "Lehi spoke to Laman and Lemuel in the valley of_____, with great power.",
    "answer": "Lemuel"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14",
    "question": "Lehi spoke to his eldest sons with great power because he was filled with the____ of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel’s frame_____ because of the spirit of the Lord in Lehi.  (a) rocked (b) rolled(c) shook-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The words that Lehi spoke confounded Laman and Lemuel.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi writes that Lehi lived in a pretty nice house.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the words Lehi spoke to Laman and Lemuel they did not utter a word against him.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Who was exceedingly young and large in stature?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi did not have a great desire to know of the mysteries of God.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": " Nephi cried unto God so that he could know of his_____.",
    "answer": "Mysteries"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s heart was softened when he cried unto the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who did the Lord visit when he cried unto him?  (a) Laman (b) Lamuel(c) Nephi-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:16",
    "question": "Because his heart was softened: Nephi, believed all the_____ which had been spoken by his father.",
    "answer": "Words"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sam the brother of Nephi; did not believe in the words that Nephi had spoken to him. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " What brother believed Nephi’s words when he spoke to them concerning the things which the Lord had manifested unto him? (a) Laman, (b) Lemuel(c) Sam  (C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:18",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel would not _____ unto the words that Nephi said to them.",
    "answer": "Hearken"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi cried unto the Lord because of the _____ of the hearts of his two older brothers.  (a) heads (b) hardness(c) softness-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep2:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was grieved because of the hardness of the hearts of his two older brothers. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:19",
    "question": "Who did the Lord visit because of his faith and his lowliness of heart?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of his faith, Nephi diligently sought the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who did the Lord say that he would lead to a promise land? (a) Nephi (b) Lehi(c) Laman-(A) 1Nep2:20 & 1Nep18:",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "22-23"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep2:19-20",
    "question": "Who is the first person the Lord said these words to “in as-much as ye shall keep my commandments, ye shall prosper”.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord did not prepare a choice land that was above all other lands for Nephi. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep2:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " In as much as Laman and Lemuel rebel against_____; they shall be cut off from the presence of the Lord.  (a) Lehi (b) Nephi(c) Ishmael",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Nephi1Nep2:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Who did the Lord say needed to keep his commandments and he would be made a teacher and ruler over his older brothers? ",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:22"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Who was chosen to be a ruler and a teacher over his brothers?_____",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "ref": "1Nep2:22"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In the day that Laman and Lemuel rebel against the Lord, he would curse them with a sore curse.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep2:23"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Laman and Lemuel’s seed shall have no power over the seed of Nephi unless they_____ against the Lord also. ",
    "answer": "Rebel",
    "ref": "1Nep2:23"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi returned to his____ after he had spoken to the Lord.  (a) house (b) tent(c) sanctuary-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " In a dream, Lehi was_____ by the Lord to send Nephi and his older brothers back to Jerusalem.  (a) told (b) commanded(c) asked-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Who had a record of the Jews and also a genealogy of Lehi’s forefathers?",
    "answer": "Laban",
    "ref": "1Nep3:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " What type of metal plates was the record of the Jews engraved on? (a) Gold (b) Silver(c) Brass-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi required that Nephi and his brothers get the record from Laban.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep3:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers did not go the house of Laban, instead they went to work. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep3:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who did Laman and Lemuel murmur against, saying it was a hard thing that the Lord had required of them.  (a) Lehi (b) God(c) Nephi-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi and his older brothers were required and not commanded to go to the house of Laban by the Lord. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep3:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Who was favored of the Lord because he did not murmur of the thing that the Lord had commanded of him? ",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Nephi did as he was commanded. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep3:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Nephi said, “I know that the Lord gives no_____ unto the children of men unless he shall prepare a way for them that they may accomplish the thing which he commands them”. ",
    "answer": "Commandments",
    "ref": "1Nep3:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi was pleased because of the words Nephi had said, concerning the commandments of the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep3:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Nephi and his brothers went up to what city to get the plates?",
    "answer": "Jerusalem",
    "ref": "1Nep3:9"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers did not consult with one another when they got to Jerusalem for the plates. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep3:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " How did Nephi and his brothers do to decide which one of them would go to the house of Laban to get the plates? (a) draw straws (b) cast lots(c) played paper, rock, scissors.  (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Who was the first person decided upon to go to the house of Laban to get the brass plates?_____",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "ref": "1Nep3:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Concerning the plates, Laman talked with Laban in his_____. (a) house (b) tent(c) treasury-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Laman desired of Laban the records which were engraved upon the plates of brass. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep3:12"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " The plates of brass contained the_____ of Nephi’s father. ",
    "answer": "Genealogy",
    "ref": "1Nep3:12"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Laban welcomed Laman with open arms and hugs when he arrived to his house. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep3:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Laban did not want to give the brass plates to Laman. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep3:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Laban accused Laman of being a _____. (a) thief (b) robber(c) swindler. (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Who fled out of the presence of Laban and told Nephi and his brothers what Laban had done? ",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "ref": "1Nep3:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi and his brothers began to be exceedingly_____ because of the things Laban had done.  (a) sorrowful (b) angry(c) crazy-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers were about to return to their father in the wilderness because of what Laban had done. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep3:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Who said: “As the Lord lives, and as we live, we will not go down unto our father until we have accomplished the things he has commanded”. ",
    "answer": "Nephi",
    "ref": "1Nep3:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Wherefore, let us be faithful in keeping the_____ of the Lord. (a) statues (b) laws(c) commandments-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": " Lehi left behind all his gold, silver, and all manner of riches when he left Jerusalem.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep3:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi knew that Jerusalem must be destroyed because of the _____ of the people. (a) filthiness (b) lawlessness (c)wickedness (C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " The _____ of Jerusalem rejected the words of the prophets. ",
    "answer": "Jews",
    "ref": "1Nep3:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said: 'it is the wisdom in God that we should obtain these records'. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep3:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " And behold, it is wisdom in God that we should obtain these records that we may preserve the_____ of our fathers. ",
    "answer": "Language",
    "ref": "1Nep3:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wanted to preserve the words that had been spoken by the holy prophets unto his children. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep3:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " The words of the holy prophets have been delivered to them by the Spirit and _____ of God, since the world began, even down to the present time. ",
    "answer": "Power",
    "ref": "1Nep3:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi wanted to persuade Laman and Lemuel to _____ (a) slay Laban (b) bribe Laban(c) be faithful in keeping the commandments of God. (C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:21"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Nephi and his brothers went down to the land of their inheritance and gathered their gold, silver, and their_____ things. ",
    "answer": "Precious",
    "ref": "1Nep3:22"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers wanted to trade their gold, silver and their precious things for the brass plates. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep3:24"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " When Laban saw the property of Nephi and his brothers and that it was exceedingly great, he did_____ after it.  (a) desire (b) seek(c) lust-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:25"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers fled from Laban and had to leave their property behind which fell into the hands of Zoram. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep3:26"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who did Laban send to slay Nephi and his brothers? (a) his bodyguards (b) his servants(c) his army (B) 1Nep3:",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "26-27"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Where did Nephi and his brothers hide that the servants of Laban could not overtake them? (a) shed (b) forest(c) cavity of a rock-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:27"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Who was angry with Nephi, Lehi and Lemuel? ",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "ref": "1Nep3:28"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": " Lemuel would not hearken unto Nephi, but hearkened unto_____. ",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "ref": "1Nep3:28"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep3:28-29",
    "question": "An angel appeared to Laman and Lemuel as they hit Nephi and his younger brother with a rod.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The angel told Laman and Lemuel that the Lord had chosen Nephi to be a ruler over them. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep3:29"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Laman and Lemuel were told by the angel that the Lord had chosen Nephi to be ruler over them because of their_____.  (a) partying (b) slothfulness(c) iniquities-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:29"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:29",
    "question": "The angel told the sons of Lehi that the_____ would deliver Laban into their hands.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep3:31",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel began to_____ when the angel departed.",
    "answer": "Murmur"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " How many men did Laman and Lemuel say that Laban can command to slay them? (a) 30 (b) 40(c) 50  (C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep3:31"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who is mightier than Laban and his fifty? (a) Nephi, (b) Laman,(c) The Lord-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep4:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:2",
    "question": "Who spoke to the waters of the Red Sea and they divided?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When Moses and Nephi’s forefathers came through the Red Sea it had not yet dried. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep4:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:2",
    "question": "The armies of the_____ followed Moses and the Israelites and were drowned in the waters of the Red Sea.",
    "answer": "Pharaoh"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel knew that the things concerning Moses were not true. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep4:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi told his brothers that they knew that an angel of the Lord had spoken to them and they should not doubt. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep4:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:4",
    "question": "Nephi said the Lord can deliver them even as their fathers, and to destroy Laban, even as he did to the_____.",
    "answer": "Egyptians"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi went to Laban's house during a sunny afternoon. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep4:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:6",
    "question": "Nephi was led to the house of Laban by the_____ even though he did not know what to do.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:7",
    "question": "What in the name of the man that Nephi saw and had fallen to the earth because he had too much wine?",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep4:9",
    "question": "The hilt of Laban’s sword was made of pure gold and the blade of precious steel.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who told Nephi to slay Laban? (a) the Spirit (b) Laman or (c) Lemuel-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep4:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " How many times had Nephi killed before he took Laban’s life? (a) 1 (b) 2 or (c) Never-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep4:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:10-12",
    "question": "The Spirit told Nephi _____ times to slay Laban.",
    "answer": "3"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The Lord slays the _____ to bring to forth his righteous purposes. (a) ugly (b) rich or (c) wicked-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep4:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who said “it is better that one man should perish than that a nation should dwindle and perish in unbelief” (a) Nephi (b) Lehi or (c) The Lord-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep4:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The law of Moses was engraved upon the (a) gold plates (b) brass plates or (c) neither-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep4:15-16"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi did not know that the Lord had delivered Laban into his hands. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep4:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who commanded Nephi to get the records from Laban? (a) Laman (b) Lehi or (c) the Lord-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep4:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi did not obey the Spirit, and decided not to slay Laban. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep4:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:18",
    "question": "Nephi slew_____ by grabbing his hair and cutting of his head with his own sword.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi put on Laban’s garments and armor about his loins so that he could fool his servant. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep4:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Where did Laban store the brass plates? (a) his house (b) his treasury or (c) safe deposit box-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep4:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi commanded Laban’s servant with the voice of Laban that he should go with him to the treasury.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep4:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:20,35",
    "question": "What servant of Laban had the keys to the treasury?",
    "answer": "Zoram"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:21",
    "question": "The servant thought that Nephi was _____ because he had his garments and the sword girded about his loins.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Laban had been out with the elders of the Jews before he was slain.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep4:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The things we call the “Brass Plates” are never referred as such in the Book of Mormon. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep4:24,4:38,5:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep13:13,19:21,22:30",
    "question": "The things we call the “Brass Plates” are only referred to as the Plates of_____ in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "Brass"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers thought that Nephi was Laban and were exceedingly frightened. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep4:28"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi made a covenant with Zoram that he would not harm him.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep4:32-33"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi told Zoram if he would follow him and his brothers that he would be a _____ like them. (a) free (b) happy guy or (c) virtuous man-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep4:33"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said unto Zoram “Surely the Lord hath commanded us to do this thing”. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep4:34"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:35",
    "question": "Zoram promised Nephi and his brothers that he would go down to the _____ and tarry with them from that time forth.",
    "answer": "Wilderness"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep4:37",
    "question": "When_____ made an oath to Nephi and his brothers their fears concerning him ceased.",
    "answer": "Zoram"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi’s mothers’ name was (a) Sarah (b) Akish or  (c) Sariah-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep5:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Sariah had truly mourned because of her_____.  (a) aches (b) husband or (c) sons-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep5:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sariah complained to Lehi about leaving the land of their inheritance.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep5:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sariah said that Lehi was a “visionary man”",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep5:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:4",
    "question": "Lehi said that if he had not seen the things of God in a vision he would not have known the_____ of God, and perished with his brethren.",
    "answer": "Goodness"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:5",
    "question": "Lehi told Sariah that he had obtained a land or promise and knew that the Lord would deliver his sons out of the hands of _____.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sariah was comforted by the words that Lehi said concerning the land of promise and their sons. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep5:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When her sons returned from the wilderness, Sariah said that now she knew that the Lord had commanded Lehi and delivered her sons from Laban. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep5:7,8"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who commanded Lehi to flee into the wilderness?  (a) Elders of the Jews (b) the Lord or (c) Moses-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep5:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " And it came to pass, that they did rejoice exceedingly, and did offer_____ and burnt offerings unto the Lord.  (a) gold (b) sacrifice or (c) silver-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep5:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi searched the brass plateds diligently.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep5:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi beheld that the plates of brass contained the 6 books of Moses",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep5:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:11",
    "question": "The five books of Moses gave an account of the creation of the world and also of _____, who were our first parents.",
    "answer": "Adam and Eve"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:12",
    "question": "The five books of Moses also gave a record of the Jews from the beginning; even down to the commencement of the reign of king _____.",
    "answer": "Zedekiah"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The five books of Moses also contained the prophecies of the holy prophets from the beginning, even down the commencement of the reign of Zedekiah. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep5:12"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "",
    "question": "",
    "answer": "Israel"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:12",
    "question": "Moses’ books also contained the prophecies spoken by the mouth of what prophet? Who was arrested during the reign of Zedekiah on suspicion of desertion.",
    "answer": "Jeremiah"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The record that Lehi beheld contained many prophecies which have been spoken by the mouth of Jeremiah the prophet. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep5:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep5:14",
    "question": "Joseph was the son of _____, who was sold into Egypt.",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The reason Laban had the brass plates was that, he also was a descendant of Joseph who was sold into Egypt",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep5:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said that the plates of brass should never perish, nor be dimmed any more by time",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep5:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi said that they had obtained the records and searched them and found that they were of great_____ unto them.  (a) calamities (b) worth or (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep5:21"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said it is wisdom in him, that they should carry the plates of brass into the wilderness",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep5:22"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi did not give the genealogy of his fathers because they had already been given in the record that Lehi had. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep6:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep6:3",
    "question": "Nephi desired to save room in the plates so he could write the things of _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote things which were pleasing unto the world",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep6:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi gave a commandment unto his seed to write only things which were of great worth unto the children of men",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep6:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep7:1",
    "question": "Who commanded Lehi’s sons to take the daughters of Ismael to wife; to raise up seed unto the Lord in the land of promise?",
    "answer": ["God", "Lord"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep7:2",
    "question": "Nephi and his brethren were commanded by the Lord to return to Jerusalem and get _____ and his family, into the wilderness with them.",
    "answer": "Ishmael"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord softened the heart of Ishmael and his household.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep7:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Some of Ishmeal’s sons and daughters desired to return to the land of Jerusalem",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep7:6-7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi asked his older brothers- “How is it that ye have forgotten that ye have seen an angel of the Lord?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep7:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " What must we do for the Lord to do all things according to his will? (a) exercise faith in him (b) obey his commandments or (c) obey our parents-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep7:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The people of Jerusalem rejected the prophets and cast the prophet_____ into prison. (a) Zedekiah (b) Samuel the Lamanite or (c) Jeremiah-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep7:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Spirit of the Lord ceased to strive in the people of Jerusalem because they had cast out the prophets. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep7:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep7:15",
    "question": "Who told Nephi to tell Laman and Lemuel not to go back to Jerusalem or they would perish also?",
    "answer": ["God", "Lord"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Laman and Lemuel became angry with Nephi and bound him with cords and sought to take away his life",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep7:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " How did Nephi loosen the cords that he was bound with? (a) butter knife (b) sharp steak knife (c) prayed unto the Lord for strength-(C) 1Nep7:",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "17-18"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who witnessed the power of God when Nephi's bonds were released? (a) Joseph (b) Sam (c) Laman-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Neph17:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the words of Ismael’s son and others, the hearts of Laman and Lemuel were softened and they did not desire to take away the life of Nephi for a second time. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep7:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep7:19",
    "question": "The wife of_____defended Nephi with her daughter against Laman and Lemuel.",
    "answer": "Ishmael"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers bowed down before him and pleaded for forgiveness for what they had done to him",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep7:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep7:21",
    "question": "Nephi forgave his brothers for all that they had done to him and exhorted them that they should pray unto the Lord their ____ for forgiveness.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi and his family gathered together all manner of _____ of every kind. (a) animals (b) seeds or (c) wild beasts-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:2",
    "question": "While Lehi tarried in the wilderness he spoke to his sons and said he had a dream; or, in other words, I have seen a _____.",
    "answer": "Vision"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:3",
    "question": "Because of the things that he saw in his vision, Lehi had a reason to rejoice in his sons Nephi and _____.",
    "answer": "Sam"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In Lehi’s vision, he saw that many of the seed of Nephi and Sam would be saved. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Because of his vision Lehi feared exceedingly for____ and Lamuel.",
    "answer": "Laman",
    "ref": "1Nep8:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi saw in his vision a man dressed in a white_____, and he came and stood before him.  (a) shirt (b) long coat or (c) robe-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The man dressed in a white robe asked Lehi to follow him. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi traveled for many hours in darkness and began to pray to the Lord to have_____ on him.  (a) pity (b) mercy or (c) sympathy-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "And it came to pass after Lehi prayed unto the Lord he beheld a large and_____ field.",
    "answer": "Spacious",
    "ref": "1Nep8:9"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi saw a vision of a tree whose fruit was desirable to make one happy.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "As Lehi partook of the fruit of the tree he beheld that it was most sweet and white to exceed all the whiteness that he had ever seen.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " When Lehi partook of the fruit thereof it filled his _____ with exceeding great joy. (a) head (b) soul or (c) body-(B) 1",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Nep8:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi desired that his family would partake of the fruit also, because he knew that it was desirable above all other fruit. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi beheld that a river of water that ran along and near the tree of the fruit that he was partaking of.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi and part of his family realized that the fruit of the tree was most desirable above all other fruit.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:14-16"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep8:14,16",
    "question": "Lehi saw in his vision that Nephi, Sam, and_____, partook of the fruit of the tree.",
    "answer": "Sariah"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Laman and Lamuel did not partake of the fruit of the tree.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:17-18"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The _____ of iron extended along the bank of the river and led to the tree of life. (a) shaft (b) pipe or (c) rod-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Lehi beheld a straight and_____ path, which came along the rod of iron. ",
    "answer": "Narrow",
    "ref": "1Nep8:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The straight and narrow path also led unto the large and spacious field. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi referred to the large and spacious field as if had been a world. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Lehi saw numberless_____ of people who were pressing forward that they might obtain the path that led to the tree. ",
    "answer": "Concourses",
    "ref": "1Nep8:21"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "And it came to pass that a great_____ of darkness arose. ",
    "answer": "Mist",
    "ref": "1Nep8:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The mist of darkness caused a lot of people to wander off and lose their way to the tree of life.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi beheld others pressing forward and_____ to the rod of iron and partake of the fruit of the tree.  (a) holding (b) hanging or (c) clinging-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "After they had partaken of the fruit of the tree, the people cast their eyes about as if they were ashamed. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Lehi cast his eyes round about, and beheld, on the other side of the river of water, a_____ and spacious building. ",
    "answer": "Great",
    "ref": "1Nep8:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The great and spacious building stood as if it were in the air and high above the earth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "The great and spacious building was filled with people, both old and young, both_____ and female. ",
    "answer": "Male",
    "ref": "1Nep8:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The people in the great and spacious building were dress exceedingly _____. (a) ugly (b) terrible or (c) fine-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The people in the great and spacious building pointed their _____ and made fun of Nephi and all of those that partook of the fruit of the tree. (a) guns (b) spears or (c) fingers-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And after they had tasted of the fruit they were ashamed, because of those that were scoffing at them, and they fell away into forbidden paths and were lost. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:28"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi spoke of all the words of his father; concerning the vision that he had. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep8:29"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi saw other multitudes pressing forward, continually holding fast to the rod of iron. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:30"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi saw other multitudes_____ their way towards the great and spacious building.  (a) holding (b) feeling or (c) clinging-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:31"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi saw many drowned in the depths of the fountain and were lost from his view. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:32"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi also saw in his vision that many were wandering in strange_____.  (a) roads (b) paths or (c) highways-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:32"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " In Lehi’s vision great was the multitude that_____.  (a) took of the Rod of Iron (b) entered into that strange building or (c) entered into the straight and narrow path-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:33"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "After they had entered into the strange building, they pointed their fingers to Nephi and scorned at him and those that had partaken of the fruit. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep8:33"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Laman and____ did not partake of the fruit according to Lehi. ",
    "answer": "Lemuel",
    "ref": "1Nep8:35"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Lehi feared exceedingly for Laman and Lemuel lest they should be cast off from the presence of the_____. ",
    "answer": "Lord",
    "ref": "1Nep8:36"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi exhorted Laman and Lemuel with all the feeling of a _____ parent. (a) tender (b) grateful or (c) kind-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep8:37"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "After Lehi preached unto Laman and Lemuel, he prophesied unto them many things and bade them to keep the_____. ",
    "answer": "Commandments",
    "ref": "1Nep8:38"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "And all these things did my father see, and hear, and_____, as he dwelt in a tent, in the valley of Lemuel.",
    "answer": "Speak",
    "ref": "1Nep9:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " What is the name of the valley where Lehi saw, heard, and spoke of many great things?  (a) Death Valley (b) Lemuel or (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep9:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi saw, heard, and spoke of many great things that cannot be written upon the plates of Nephi. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep9:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The plates of Nephi are given that name because they contain a full account of the history of the people of _____. (a) Christ (b) Nephi or (c) Lehi-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep9:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi knew that in the future, there would be a reign of kings among his people.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep9:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The plates of Nephi are written mostly of his ministry.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep9:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "The other plates that are written are for the more part of the reign of_____ and the wars and contentions of the people of Nephi. ",
    "answer": "Kings",
    "ref": "1Nep9:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi made another set of plates that he did not know for what purpose.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep9:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said the “Lord knows all things from the beginning; wherefore, he prepares a way to accomplish all his works among the children of men”.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep9:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Lehi exhorted his sons with all diligence and also spoke to them concerning the_____ at Jerusalem. ",
    "answer": "Jews",
    "ref": "1Nep10:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Lehi said that Jerusalem would be destroyed and many would be carried away captive to _____. ",
    "answer": "Babylon",
    "ref": "1Nep10:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said that the Jews would be brought back out of captivity and possess again the land of their inheritance, in the Lords’ own due time. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "The Lord God would rise up a _____ 600 years after Lehi left Jerusalem.-Messiah or",
    "answer": "Savior",
    "ref": "1Nep10:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said that the Messiah would only be a savior to the most righteous people of the world.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep10:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Lehi also spoke concerning the prophets and how great a number had testified concerning the_____. ",
    "answer": "Messiah",
    "ref": "1Nep10:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Nephi also referred to the Savior as the_____ of the world. ",
    "answer": "Redeemer",
    "ref": "1Nep10:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "“Wherefore, all mankind were in a lost and in a_____ state, and ever would be save they should rely on this redeemer”. ",
    "answer": "Fallen",
    "ref": "1Nep10:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi also spoke of a_____ who should come before the Messiah, to prepare the way of the Lord.  (a) person (b) man or (c) prophet-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep10:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon never mentions John the Baptist by name.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:7-10, 1Nep11:27, 2Nep31:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Book of Mormon only references John the Baptist three times and never by name, but only as a prophet. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:7-10, 1Nep11:27, 2Nep31:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who predicted the birth, baptism, death, and resurrection of the Messiah?_____.-(a) Lehi (b) Laban) (c) Zoram-(A) 1Nep10:",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "7-11"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "",
    "question": "",
    "answer": ""
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "This prophet of the Lord would go forth and cry in the wilderness:”Prepare ye the way of the Lord, and make his paths straight”. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:8",
    "question": "For there stands one among you whom ye know not, whose____ latchet I am not worthy to unloose.",
    "answer": "shoe"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The prophet of the Lord said that there was one among them that was mightier than him. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "INep10:9",
    "question": "What is the name of the place where Lehi said that the Messiah would be baptized?",
    "answer": "Bethabara"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi said that Bethabara was located by_____. (a) Utah (b) Iowa or (c) beyond Jordan-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "INep10:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who would baptize the Messiah with water? (a) Alma (b) a prophet or (c) Mosiah-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep10:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said that the prophet that would baptize the Lamb of God should behold and bear record that he was the Messiah, and should take away the sins of the world. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who would bear record that he baptized the Lamb of God? (a) Nephi (b) Laman or (c) a prophet-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep10:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi spoke to Nephi’s brothers concerning the gospel which should be preached among the Jews and their dwindling in unbelief. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:11",
    "question": "Who did Lehi say would slay the Messiah?",
    "answer": "jews"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:11",
    "question": "Lehi said that the Messiah would rise from the dead and make himself manifest by the _____ unto the Gentiles.",
    "answer": "Holy Ghost"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Gentiles and the house of Israel would be compared like unto an olive-tree and should be scattered upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:13",
    "question": "Lehi said that they should be led with one accord into the land of_____ unto the fulfilling of the word of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Promise"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " When Lehi prophesied about the Gentiles and the house of Israel he dwelt in a tent, in the valley of _____. (a) Gideon (b) Lemuel or (c) neither -(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep10:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi heard all the words of his father, concerning the things which he saw in a vision. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:17",
    "question": "By what power did Lehi prophesy the things concerning the Gentiles and the house of Israel?",
    "answer": "Holy Ghost"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What is the gift given to all those who diligently seek God?",
    "options": ["Eternal Life", "Holy Ghost", "Eternal Happiness"],
    "answer": "Holy Ghost",
    "ref": "1Nep10:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " We receive the power of the Holy Ghost by having_____ in the Son of God.  (a) faith (b) diligence or (c) contrite spirit-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep10:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The way is prepared for all men from the foundation of the world, if it so be that they repent and come unto him. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " By the power of the Holy Ghost the _____ of God are revealed to those that diligently seek him. (a) things (b) mysteries or (c) secrets-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep10:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep10:21",
    "question": "Wherefore, if ye have sought to do wickedly in the days of your_____, then ye are found unclean before the judgment-seat of God.",
    "answer": "Probation"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "If you are unclean and repent you can still enter the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep10:21"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who gave authority to Nephi to speak and write the things he did and not deny them? (a) Jesus Christ (b) Holy Ghost or (c) God-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep10:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "We are free to act for ourselves-to choose the way of everlasting death or the way of eternal life.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep10:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi desired to know the things which his father had seen.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep11:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:1",
    "question": "Nephi was carried away in the _____ of the Lord into an exceedingly high mountain.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The name of the mountain that Nephi was carried away is named. (a) Sinai (b) Hoeb or (c) we don’t know -(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep11:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was to witness and bear record that the man he saw descending out of heaven, was the Son of God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep11:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi beheld that the tree the Spirit of Lord showed him, exceeded the whiteness of the driven snow.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep11:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The tree that Nephi was shown by the Spirit was precious above all things.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep11:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi beheld in his vision, the city of Nazareth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep11:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:13",
    "question": "Nephi saw in his vision a _____ who was exceedingly fair and white.",
    "answer": "Virgin"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:1",
    "question": "Who did Nephi see that was the mother of the Son of God, after the manner of the flesh?",
    "answer": "Virgin"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Mos3:8, Alma7:",
    "question": "What is the name of the Savior's mother?",
    "answer": "Mary"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When Nephi beheld the virgin the second time, she was bearing a child in her arms.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep11:19-20"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Spirit of the Lord asked Nephi if he knew the condescension of God.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep11:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:21",
    "question": "Other names for the Savior are_____of God and Son of the Eternal Father.",
    "answer": "Lamb"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The angel said that the love of God is the most joyous to the soul.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1 Nep11:23"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:25",
    "question": "What did the Rod of Iron represent in Lehi’s vision?",
    "answer": "Word"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep11:27",
    "question": "The Holy Ghost appeared in the form of a_____ after Jesus Christ was baptized.",
    "answer": "Dove"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who was gathered together to fight against the apostles of the Lamb of God. (a) Israel (b) people of the earth or (c) Lamanites-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep11:33"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi saw in his vision the great and spacious building fall.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep11:36"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who is to judge the twelve tribes of Israel? (a) God (b) Jesus Christ or (c) 12 Apostles of the Lamb of God-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep12:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi beheld his seed and the seed of his brothers gathered together to do battle one with another. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep12:1-2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi saw the land of promise in his vision.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep12:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi saw the heavens open and Jesus Christ descending out of heaven and appearing to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep12:6, 2Nep26:1,9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Because of the _____ in the Lamb of God the garments of the twelve disciples are made white in his blood. (a) faith (b) greatness or (c) the ivory soap-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep12:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Because of their faith, _____generations passed away in righteousness and their garments were made white, even like unto the Lamb of God. (a) 2 (b) 12 or (c) 3-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep12:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Another name that can describe the fountain of filthy water and the depths thereof is. (a) The Amazon (b) The Euphrates (c) Hell-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep12:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The mists of darkness which Nephi saw are the temptations of the devil.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep12:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Another name that can be used to describe the large and spacious building which Lehi saw are; the vain imaginations of the children of men.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep12:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep12:18",
    "question": "What personage bears record from the beginning of the world to Nephi’s time and forever that Jesus Christ is the Messiah?",
    "answer": "Holy Ghost"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " What leads men to broad roads; that they perish and are lost? (a) false prophets (b) false doctrine or (c) temptations of the devil-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep12:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who was the angel referring to when he said to Nephi “behold these shall dwindle in unbelief”. - (B)",
    "options": ["Nephites", "Lamanites", "Gentiles"],
    "answer": "Lamanites",
    "ref": "1Nep12:22-23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of their pagan beliefs, the Lamanites became a dark, loathsome, and filthy people",
    "answer": "F",

    "ref": "1Nep12:23, 2Nep5:21"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi saw among the nations of the Gentiles, the foundation of a great church.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep13:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The abominable church slays the saints of God, and tortures and binds them down with a yoke of iron. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep13:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep13:6",
    "question": "Who is the founder foundation of the great and abominable church?",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Of all these things-which is not a desire of the great abominable church? (a) precious jewels (b) gold or (c) silks-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep13:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The abominable church destroys the saints of God and brings them down into captivity for the praise of the world. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep13:9"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep13:10",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Nephi looked and saw many waters that divided the Gentiles from the seed of his_____.",
    "answer": "Brethren"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The angel told Nephi to look and see that the_____ of God was upon the seed of his brethren.  (a) hand (b) wrath or (c) spirit-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep13:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In his vision Nephi saw who we know as Christopher Columbus.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep13:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi saw what was later to be known as the Revolutionary War in our time?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep13:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The book that the angel showed Nephi proceeded out of the mouth of a Jew",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep13:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When the book first proceeded from the mouth of the Jew, it contained the purity and plainness of the Gospel?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep13:24-25"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who or what took away the many plain parts and precious things from the Bible? (a) Moses (b)  Abominable Church or (c) The Jews- (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep13:28"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the taking away of many plain and precious things from the book/bible, many people stumble and Satan has great power over them.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep13:29"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who or what is the mother of all harlots? (a) Eve (b) Abominable Church (c) Wickedness-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep13:34"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep13:37",
    "question": "In what Book of Mormon book do the words “endure unto the end” first mentioned?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " What prophet of the Lord is the first to use the words “endure unto the end”? (a) Nephi (b) King Benjamin or (c) Alma the Elder-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep13:37"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi saw the book of the Lamb or God, which had proceeded forth from the mouth of the Jew, come unto the seed of his brethren?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep13:38"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi saw other _____ which would testify to the convincing that the record of Jews and twelve apostles of the Lamb of God are true. (a) a proclamation (b) other books (c) A Marvelous Work and a Wonder-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep13:39"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Book of Mormon Pictures",
    "question": "What animal appears in the Book of Mormon picture where Lehi is holding the Liahona?",
    "answer": "Camal"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi saw the last records that were among the Gentiles which would establish the truth of the Bible.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep13:40"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who must come unto the Savior in order to be saved? (a) old people (b) sick people or (c) all men-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep13:40"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " There is only one God and one_____over all the earth. (a) prophet (b) angel or (c) Shepherd-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep13:41"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep13:40-42",
    "question": "The angel said that the last shall be first, and the first shall be _____.",
    "answer": "Last"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "If the Gentiles hearken unto the Lamb of God, he would manifest himself unto them; in word, in power and in deed",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep14:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who will fill the great pit that was dug for the destruction of men? (a) Those that are not baptize (b) The Wicked or (c) Those that digged it-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep14:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The great and abominable church and its founders, were the ones who dug the great pit?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep14:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " _____ be unto the Gentiles if it so be that they harden their hearts against the Lamb of God. (a) Too Bad (b) Dang it! or (c) Woe-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep14:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep14:7",
    "question": "The Lord will work a great and _____work among the children of men.",
    "answer": "Marvelous"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The marvelous work that the Lord will bring forth, will be everlasting –either to the convincing of them or life eternal or unto the deliverance of the hardness of their hearts.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep14:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep14:7",
    "question": "Who will bring down men into captivity both temporally and spiritually?",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The angel asked Nephi if he could remember the covenants the Lord had made with the house of Israel.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep14:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " In First Nephi, the angel said there are only ____ churches? (a) One (b) Two or (c) Three -(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep14:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The angel revealed to Nephi the _____ of all the earth? (a) wickedness (b) whore or (c) history-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep14:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who will gather great multitudes of people to do battle with the Lamb of God? (a) Osama Bin Laden (b) Moammar Kadafi or (c) Great Abominable Church-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep14:9,13"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who was armed with righteousness and with the power of God in great glory, to do battle with the great and Abominable Church? (a) The Jews (b) saints of the Lamb of God or (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep14:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Another name we can use to describe the Great and Abominable Church is the “mother of harlots”",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep14:16-17"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi beheld a man dressed in a white robe, who was one of the twelve apostles of the Lamb of God?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep14:19-20"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep14:20,21,27",
    "question": "The angel showed Nephi _____ the Revelator.",
    "answer": "John"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi bore record to us that he saw John the Revelator. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep14:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi writes that John the Revelator will write things that have been concerning the world and also of the end thereof. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep:14:21"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " In what book are the things written that John the Apostle wrote? (a) National Enquire (b) The Bible or (c) Wall Street Journal-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep14:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was allowed to see all the things that have been and the ending of the world as we know it?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep14:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was commanded to write and bear record of all the things he saw by the Angel of the Lord?",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep14:25, 27-28"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi is not the only person that has seen things that have been and things that are to come of this world?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "-1Nep14:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi testified and bear record of the things his father Lehi saw?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep14:29"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi saw his brothers disputing one with another concerning the things Lehi had spoken to them?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was grieved and afflicted because he saw the destruction and fall of his people. Nephities?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:4-5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers did not inquire of the Lord concerning the natural branches of the olive-tree and the Gentiles?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:7-9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The house of Israel is compared to an_____ tree in the first book of Nephi. (a) peach (b) apple or (c) olive  (C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep15:12"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers’ seed will eventually come to the knowledge that they are of the house of Israel though the gospel of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " In whose seed shall all the kindred’s of the earth be blessed? (a) Nephi’s (b) Lehi’s or (c) Abraham’s-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep15:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " What prophet spoke concerning the restoration of the Jews in the latter days? (a) Moses (b) Isaiah or (c) Lehi-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep15:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "According to the prophet Isaiah, after the Jews are restored to the gospel, they will never again be confounded or scattered again. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers wanted to know what the tree meant that Lehi saw in his dream.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:21"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The tree that Lehi saw was a representation on the Tree of Life?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "One way we can fight off the fiery darts and the temptations of the devil is by hearkening and holding on to the Rod of Iron?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said the river of water that separates the wicked from God and also his saints.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:27-28"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep15:30",
    "question": "The justice of God divides the _____ from the righteous.",
    "answer": "Wicked"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "We will be judged by the works we do when we are in our temporal bodies, and also in the days of our probation.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:32"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said there is a place already prepared for the filthy and wicked?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep15:34-35"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "Whose fruit is most precious and most desirable above all other fruits?",
    "answer": "Tree",
    "ref": "1Nep15:36"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "question": "What is the greatest of all gifts that God can bestow upon us, according to Nephi?",
    "answer": "Tree",
    "ref": "1Nep15:36"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who takes the truth to be hard and cuts them to the very center? (a) Lamanites (b) the wicked or (c) the guilty-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep16:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Zoram took the _____ daughter of Ishmael to wife? (a) prettiest (b) eldest or (c) fairest-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep16:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi found a round ball made of fine brass and of curious workmanship?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep16:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Within the ball that Lehi found was _____spindles. (a) five (b) two or (c) three-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep16:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "One of the spindles in the ball told Lehi and his family which direction they should go in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep16:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi departed into the wilderness across the _____ River. (a) Amazon (b) Euphrates or (c) Laman-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep16:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " After Lehi’s family had traveled for four days-they pitched their tents in a place called _____. (a) Egypt (b) Shazer or (c) Idaho-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep16:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi and his brothers hunted with _____ and _____.-(a) Bows and Arrows, (b) Stones and Slings(c) guns and knives",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep16:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:14,16",
    "question": "The directions of the ball led them to the more _____ parts of the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Fertile"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi’s bow was made of _____ steel. (a) expensive (b) cheap or (c) fine-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep16:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi broke his bow and his brothers got angry with him",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep16:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi and some of his sons began to murmur exceedingly because of their afflictions and sufferings in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Neph16:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi made another bow made out of_____ (a) steel (b) wood (c) fiberglass-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep16:23"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:23",
    "question": "How many arrows did Nephi make for his second bow?",
    "answer": "1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:23",
    "question": "Who said “Whither shall I go to obtain food”?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi was brought down to the depths of sorrow, for murmuring.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep16:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:29",
    "question": "Nephi said “and thus we see that by _____ means the Lord can bring about great things.",
    "answer": "Small"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep16:29",
    "question": "A new writing, which was plain to read, appeared on the ball that Lehi found.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:30-31",
    "question": "Nephi went to the _____ of a mountain to obtain food for him and his family.",
    "answer": "Top"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who died and was buried in the place which was called Nahom? (a) Ishmael (b) Lehi or (c) Zoram-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep16:34"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Ishmael’s daughters murmured against Lehi, saying that they had suffered much affliction, hunger, _____ and fatigue in the wilderness. (a) whippings (b) thirst or (c) disease-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep16:35"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep16:38-39",
    "question": "The voice of the_____ did come down and spoke and chastened Laman and Lemuel, exceedingly for murmuring.",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Lehi’s party wondered_____ years before they came upon a land that had much fruit and wild honey. (a) 3  (b) 8 or (c) 6-(B) 1Nep17:",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "4-5"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:5",
    "question": "What did Lehi and his family call: “the land that had much fruit and wild honey”?",
    "answer": "Bountiful"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:5",
    "question": "What is the name of the sea, when interpreted; means many waters?",
    "answer": "Irreantum"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And it came to pass that Lehi’s party pitched their tents by the seashore and they had suffered many afflictions and much difficulty that they could not write them all. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi was told by the Lord to construct a _____? (a) spacecraft (b) ship or (c) car-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep17:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The ship that Nephi constructed, was after the manner of men?",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep17:8-9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The food that Nephi and his brothers hunted did not have to be cooked.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": " The food that Nephi killed was made sweet by the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:12"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:16",
    "question": "Nephi made tools of the _____ which he molted out of the rock, to build the ship.",
    "answer": "Ore"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers did not believe that he had been instructed by the Lord to build the ship.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:17-18"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Nephi was exceedingly _____ because of the hardness of his brothers’ hearts. (a) angry (b) sorrowful or (c) glad-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep17:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers believed that the people they left in Jerusalem were righteous?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:23-24",
    "question": "According to Nephi-who led the Israelites out of bondage from the Egyptians?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:26",
    "question": "By whose words did the Red Sea divide hither and thither?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The armies of the Egyptians belonged to the (a) Navy Seals (b) Army’s Delta Force or (c) The Pharoah-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep17:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:29",
    "question": "Moses smote a _____ and there came forth water.",
    "answer": "Rock"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Moses and the Israelites were fed _____ in the wilderness, by God. (a) spaghettios (b) mac and cheese or (c) manna-(C) 1Nep17:",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "28-29"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The River Jordan is mentioned in the first book of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:32"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord's purpose for the creation of earth was so it should be inhabited and that his children should possess it.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:36"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " The Lord would rise up a righteous nation and destroy the nations of the _____. (a) Islam (b) Far East or (c) wicked-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep17:37"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep17:39",
    "question": "The Lord rules high up in heaven and it is his throne, and the earth is his _____.",
    "answer": "Footstool"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord esteemes all flesh in one; he that is righteous is favored of God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:35"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord sent fiery flying serpents to the Israelites in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:41"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord prepared a way for the Israelites to be healed from the fiery flying Serpents bites.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:41, Hel 8:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " What did the israelites have to do to be healed from the bites of the fiery flying serpents? (a) pray (b) call upon the Lord (c) was to look at the brazen serpent-(C) 1Nep17:41,",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Hel8:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Many of the israelites perished because they refused to look at the serpent.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:41"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi knew or saw that almost all of the Israelites that were with Moses were going to be destroyed.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:43"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": " Who said “ye are swift to do iniquity but slow to remember the Lord your God”. (a) Lehi (b) Nephi or (c) Moses-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep17:45"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who was filled with the Spirit of God that his body/frame had no strength? (a) Lehi (b) Nephi or (c) Moses-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep17:47"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How did God show Nephi’s brothers that he was “the Lord their God”? (a) startled them (b) made the earth move or (c) shocked them- (C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep17:53"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers were going to worship him after the Lord had shaken them.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep17:55"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi and his brothers worked timbers for the ship of curious workmanship.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep18:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who told Lehi to go down into the ship and prepare to sail? (a) The Lord (b) Nephi or (c) no one-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep185-6"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many sons did Lehi beget in the wilderness?_____(a) 1 (b) 2 (3)-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep18:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep18:7",
    "question": "Lehi beget two sons in the wilderness; who was the eldest? Joseph or Jacob",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord allowed Nephi to be bound by his brothers in order to fulfill his word and to show his power, concerning the wicked?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep18:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The compass that was prepared of the Lord ceased to work because Nephi had been bound by cords.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep18:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said many things to Laman, Lemuel, and the sons of Ismael because of their hardness of heart towards Nephi",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep18:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep18:18",
    "question": "Nephi’s parents suffered much grief and sorrow because the iniquity of his _____.",
    "answer": "Brothers"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep18:19",
    "question": "Jacob and Joseph needed much _____, and were grieved because of the afflictions of their mother.",
    "answer": "Nourishment"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep18:20",
    "question": "The only thing that could soften the heart of Laman and Lemuel was the power of _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Approximately when did Lehi and his family arrive in the promise land? (a) 600 B.C. (b) 601 B.C. or (c) 589 B.C.-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep18:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi and his family found all manner of wild animals and beasts in the wilderness.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep18:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi found all kinds of ore, both of silver, gold, and copper?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep18:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord commanded that only Nephi’s prophecies be engraved on the brass plates.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep19:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "1Nep19:4",
    "question": "Nephi commanded his posterity to hand down the plates from one generation to another.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi wanted that the more _____ things may be kept for the knowledge of his people. (a) secret (b) sacred or (c) important-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep19:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi only wrote the things that he deemed sacred upon the plates.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Neh19:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wanted us to forgive his weakness in writing",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep19:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who told Nephi that the Savior would come six hundred years from the time they left Jerusalem (a) little birdie (b) an angel or (c) Moses- (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep19:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The world because of their _____ will judge the Savior as a thing of naught? (a) riches (b) iniquity or (c) hatred-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep19:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jesus Christ suffered and endured all the things done to him before the crucifixion because of his loving kindness and long-suffering towards the children of men.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep19:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi said that the Savior would be lifted up according to the words of what Hebrew prophet?_____-(a) Moses (b) Zenock or (c) Jeremiah-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": " Nephi said that the Savior would be crucified according to the words of Neum; a Hebrew prophet.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The prophets Zenock and Neum said that Jesus Christ would be lifted up and be crucified.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10 & Alma33:15"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "According to the words of the prophet _____, Jesus Christ would be buried in sepulcher. (a) Abinidi (b) Moses or (c) Zenos-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10",
    "question": "Zenos the prophet; prophesied that there would be _____ days of darkness given as a sign of Jesus Christ’s death.",
    "answer": "3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Zenos said those that inhabit the isles of the sea and the house of Israel would be given more of a sign of his death?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep19:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "After the crucifixion, the Savior will visit the righteous with his voice unto their great joy and salvation.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep19:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep19:12",
    "question": "The prophet Zenos said that the kings of the isles of the sea will exclaim: The _____ of nature suffers.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The people in Jerusalem will be scourged by all people because they crucified the God of Israel.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep19:13"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep19:13-14",
    "question": "Who or what people despised the Holy One of Israel?",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep19:14,19",
    "question": "What people will become a hiss and a by-word, and be hated among all nations?",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep19:16",
    "question": "Zenos prophesied that the Lord would gather all the people that are from the house of Israel from the four _____ of the earth.",
    "answer": "Quarters"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote things to persuade his people so they would remember the Lord their Redeemer. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep19:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi knew the things concerning the prophets of old because they are written on the plates of brass Lehi had. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep19:21 & 3Nep10:16-17"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi read unto his brothers the things that were written in the book of Moses and also things written by the prophet Isaiah",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep19:23"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi liken all the scriptures unto himself and his family; that it would be for their profit and _____. (a) understanding  (b) learning or (c) good-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep19:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Another name for the house of Israel is _____ (a) house of Abraham (b) house of Jacob or (c) house of righteousness-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep20:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord said that he had laid the foundation of the earth and my left hand has spanned the heavens. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep20:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord told the House of Israel that if they would hearken to his commandments-then their peace be as a river, and their righteousness as the waves of the sea. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep20:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "There is no peace, saith the Lord, unto the _____. (a) humble (b) wicked or (c) Israelites-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep20:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": " The prophet Isaiah will raise up the tribes of Jacob and also be a light unto the Gentiles? ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": ") 1Nep21:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Kings will see and arise; princes also shall worship, because the Lord that is faithful. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep21:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep21:16",
    "question": "The Lord has engraved the house of Israel upon the _____ of his hands.",
    "answer": "Palms"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Isaiah said the Lord would lift up his hand to the Gentiles. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep21:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who said “I will contend with him that contends with thee”. (a) Isaiah (b) Lehi or (c) the Lord-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep21:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord refers to himself as the Mighty One of_____. (a) Nephi (b) Lehi or (c) Jacob-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep21:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that “by the Spirit are all things made known unto the prophets”. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep22:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep22:3",
    "question": "The writings of Isaiah that Nephi read to his brothers were both _____ and spiritual.",
    "answer": "Temporal"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi told his brothers that the house of Israel, sooner or later, will be scattered upon all the earth and nations. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep22:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who should not fear the wrath of God? (a) the righteous (b) Nephites or (c) Lamanites-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep22:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi declared that the prophet spoken by Moses; was the Holy One of Israel.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep22:21"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Those who are built up to get gain, power, and be popular and who belong to the kingdom of the devil need to fear the wrath of God. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep22:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The righteous must be led up as _____ of the stall, and the Holy One of Israel must reign in dominion, and might, and power, and great glory. (a) sheep (b) calves or (c) neither-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep22:24"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord _____ his sheep; and they know him. (a) numbers (b) marks or (c) colors-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep22:25"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the peoples’ righteousness, Satan will have no power and the Holy One of Israel will reign for many years. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep22:26"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When the Lord comes again to reign on earth; Mormon writes that the devil will be chained for one-thousand years.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "1Nep22:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "We are never told in the Book of Mormon how long or for how many years the devil will be chained when the Lord comes to reign upon the earth at the last days.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep22:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "All kindreds, tongues, and people must repent if they are to dwell safely in the Holy One of Israel. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep22:28"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep22:29-30",
    "question": "Nephi testified that the things written in the brass plates are true and that man must be obedient to the commandments of _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi and Lehi are not the only ones that have written concerning the brass plates. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "1Nep22:30-31"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "1Nep22:31",
    "question": "We need to be obedient to the commandments and _____ to the end, to be saved in the last day.",
    "answer": "Endure"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The first book of Nephi ends with the word/words-(a) Adieu (b) Amen or (c) The End-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep22:31"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In 2Nephi the Lord covenanted with Lehi; the land of promise to him and all his seed. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi did prophesy; that no one would come to the promise land, unless they would be brought by the _____ of the Lord.  (a) Spirit (b) hand or (c) arm-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep1:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The promise land is consecrated to all of those that the Lord will bring to it. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The promise land will be a land of liberty as long as we serve the Lord according to the commandments. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "If we are brought down to captivity in the promise land; it will be because of our iniquity. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "If iniquity abounds in the promise land, it will be _____ for the people’s sake. (a) burned (b) cursed or (c) flooded-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep1:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "It is wisdom that the promise land be hid from the knowledge of other nations because it would be _____. (a) overrun (b) segregated or (c) neither-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep1:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:9",
    "question": "If Lehi and his family keep the commandments of the Lord, they would _____, in the promised land.",
    "answer": "Prosper"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi and his family/party were given power by the Lord to do all things by faith. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:10",
    "question": "Lehi and his family were brought to the precious land of promise by the Lords' _____ goodness.",
    "answer": "Infinite"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "According to Lehi:  we our bound by awful _____ of hell; that binds us captive to the eternal gulf of misery and woe. (a) people (b) chains or (c) temptations-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep1:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:14",
    "question": "Who in 2Nephi said “cold and silent grave, from whence no traveler can return”?",
    "answer": "Lehi"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi feared that his sons would be led to the will and captivity of the devil? ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:18"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:17-18",
    "question": "Who will visit Lehi’s sons by the sword and by famine?",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:19",
    "question": "Whose will is always done and his ways are righteousness forever?",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:21",
    "question": "Lehi wanted his sons to be men, and be determined in one mind and in one _____, united in all things.",
    "answer": "Heart"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi said “awake my sons; put on the armor of _____. (a) steel (b) truth or (c) righteousness-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:24",
    "question": "Which one of Lehi’s sons had been an instrument in the hands of the Lord from the beginning of their journey?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:25",
    "question": "Who sought the glory of God and the eternal welfare of his brothers during the journey to the promise land?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The sharpness that Nephi used on his brothers was the sharpness of the power of the word of God. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi could not restrain himself from manifesting boldly concerning his brother’s iniquities. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Spirit of the Lord was the one that opened Nephi’s mouth that he could not shut it. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi told his sons to hearken to the voice of _____ and they would not perish. (a) the boss (b) Nephi or (c) their mother-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep1:28"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep1:30",
    "question": "Lehi knew that _____ was led out of Jerusalem, and was a true friend of Nephi, forever.",
    "answer": "Zoram"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said that Zoram’s seed would prosper in the promise land as long as there would be no iniquity among them. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:31"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi would take away the blessings he gave Laman, Lemuel, and Sam if they did not hearken unto the voice of Nephi. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep1:28-29"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Lehi told his son Jacob- “and the way is prepared from the fall of man, and _____ is free”.  (a) bread (b) salvation or (c) life-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep2:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Men are instructed sufficiently that they know good from evil.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep2:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:6",
    "question": "Lehi said redemption comes in and through the Holy Messiah; for he is full of _____ and truth.",
    "answer": "Grace"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:7",
    "question": "The Lord offers himself a sacrifice for sin, to answer the ends of the law, unto all those who have a _____ heart and a contrite spirit.",
    "answer": "Broken"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:8",
    "question": "The Holy Messiah will bring to pass the _____ or the dead, being the first that should rise.",
    "answer": "Resurrection"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord will make intercession for all the children of men; and they that believe in him shall be saved. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep2:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:11",
    "question": "Lehi told Jacob,”for it must needs be, that there is an _____ in all things”.",
    "answer": "Opposition"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:11",
    "question": "There must be nor corruption nor _____, happiness nor misery, neither sense nor insensibility.",
    "answer": "Incorruption"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "And if ye shall say there in no law, ye also shall say there no _____. (a) mercy (b) gift or (c) sin-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep2:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi testified to his sons that there is a God and he has created all things, both the heavens and the earth. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep2:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi read that an angel of God fell from heaven; wherefore, he became a devil, having sought that which was evil before God. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep2:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:27",
    "question": "In 2Nephi- who did Lehi say “seeks that all men might be miserable like unto himself”.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Devil is quoted in the Book Of Mormon.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep2:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many times is the Devil quoted in the Book Of Mormon? (a) one (b) two or (c) 3 times.-(3) ",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep2:18, 2Nep24:13,14"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:18",
    "question": "Who is the father of all lies?",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:18",
    "question": "Who told Eve to partake of the forbidden fruit, and you shall not die, but you shall be as a God, knowing good from evil?",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:19",
    "question": "Adam and Eve were driven out of the_____ of Eden, for partaking of the forbidden fruit.",
    "answer": "Garden"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:21",
    "question": "According to the will of God; men while in the flesh might repent; wherefore, their state became a state of _____.",
    "answer": "Probation"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "If Adam hat not transgressed, things would have remained in the same state in which they were after they were created, and had no end. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep2:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "But behold, all things have been done in the _____ of him who knows all things.  (a) wisdom (b) power or (c) foresight-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep2:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:25",
    "question": "_____ fell that men might he; and men are, that they might have joy.",
    "answer": "Adam"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:26",
    "question": "The Messiah comes in the _____ of time, that he may redeem the children of men from the fall.",
    "answer": "Fulness"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:26",
    "question": "Men are free to act for themselves and not to be _____ upon.",
    "answer": "Acted"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Another name that we can use to describe Jesus Christ is the great Mediator.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep2:28"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:28",
    "question": "Lehi told his sons “I would that ye look to the great _____ and hearken unto his great commandments”.",
    "answer": "Mediator"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi wanted his sons to not to choose eternal death, according to the will of the flesh and the evil which is therein. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep2:29"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi choose the words of the prophet, and had no other objective; save it be the everlasting welfare of his son’s souls. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep2:30"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep3:1",
    "question": "Which one of Lehi’s sons was born in the days of his greatest sorrow?",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Whose seed did Lehi prophesied would not be utterly destroyed? (a) Moses (b) Joseph or (c) neither a nor b-(B) 2Nep3",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "3, 5"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep3:5",
    "question": "Who truly saw the days of the Nephites by a vision and prophecy?",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Joseph testified that a seer shall the Lord raise up from the fruit of his loins. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep3:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep3:5",
    "question": "In 2Nephi; who obtained a promise from the Lord that his posterity would be a righteous branch of Israel?",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep3:15",
    "question": "What is the seer’s first name that the Lord would raise up from Joseph’s loins?",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "They who seek to destroy the choice seer would be confounded. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep3:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "3Nep3:11",
    "question": "The Lord will give power to the seer to bring forth his word unto the seed of _____ loins.",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep3:17",
    "question": "Who would the Lord rise up and give him judgment “Unto him in writing”?",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Moses will be mighty in speaking. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "2Nep3:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord will would make a spokesman for Moses",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep3:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In the Book of Mormon we are told of the name of the spokesman that the Lord will have for Moses.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "2Nep3:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The seed of Joseph will _____ unto the words of the book/Mormon. (a) hearken (b)  Laugh or (c) be confounded-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep3:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In 2Nephi: Who will be a _____ in the hands of God? (a) instrument (b) leader or (c) accomplice-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep3:24"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Joseph was told to hearken unto the words of _____ by his father. (a) Alma (b) Nephi or (c) Mosiah-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep3:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When Lehi was prophesying to Joseph he was in his mid 20’s. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "2Nep3:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi spoke concerning prophecies of Joseph, who was carried into Egypt. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep4:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Joseph who was carried into Egypt; truly prophesied concerning all his seed. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep4:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:2",
    "question": "The prophecies of Joseph who was sold in Egypt or written upon the plates of _____.",
    "answer": "Brass"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "There are not many greater prophecies than those of Joseph who was carried into Egypt. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep4:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:3",
    "question": "Lehi called Laman and his sons, and his _____ to give ear unto his words.",
    "answer": "Daughters"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "If Laman and Lemuel seed was cursed, Lehi wanted the curse to be answered upon the heads of him and his wife. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep4:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Lehi said that Lamuel’s seed would be blessed at the end. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep4:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Whose seed will be numbered with the seed of Nephi and be blessed in all his days. (a) Laman  (b) Lemuel or (c) Sam-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep4:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:12",
    "question": "After Lehi gave his blessings to his sons he waxed old and the he _____ and the Spirit of the Lord was him.",
    "answer": "Died"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Laman, Lemuel, and Ismael were angry with Nephi because of the admonitions of the Lord. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep4:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "More of Nephi’s sayings and history are written on his other plates. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep4:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:15",
    "question": "Who said “my soul delights in the scriptures, and my heart ponders them”?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:15",
    "question": "Nephi wrote things of his soul and for the learning and the profit of his _____.",
    "answer": "Children"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:16",
    "question": "Whose soul delights in the things of the Lord, and ponders continually upon the things which I have seen and heard?- ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:16-35",
    "question": "Wrote the _____ of Nephi, shortly after the death of his father.",
    "answer": "Psalm"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:17",
    "question": "Who said “O wretched man that I am! Yea, my heart sorrows because of my flesh; my soul grieves because of mine iniquities”?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:21",
    "question": "Who is filled with the love of the Lord, even unto consuming of his flesh?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:23",
    "question": "Who cried by day, and he was given knowledge by visions in the nighttime?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:24",
    "question": "Who waxed bold in mighty prayer and angels came down and ministered unto him?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:25",
    "question": "Who was carried upon the wings of the Spirit of the Lord and away upon exceeding high mountains?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi beheld great things, yea even too great for man",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep4:25"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:25",
    "question": "Nephi was _____ to write some of the great things that he saw by the Lord?",
    "answer": "Forbidden"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who said: “Why should I yield to sin, because of my flesh”? (a) Laman (b) Lemuel or (c) Nephi-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep4:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:30",
    "question": "Who will praise the Lord forever, and his soul will rejoice in his God; the rock of his salvation?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who asked the Lord, “wilt thou not shut the gates of thy righteousness before me”? (a) Laman (b) Lemuel or (c) Nephi- (C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep4:32"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:33",
    "question": "Who said “O Lord, wilt thou encircle me around in the robe of thy righteousness”?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said “O Lord, I have trusted in thee, and I will trust in thee forever”. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep4:34"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:34",
    "question": "I will not put my _____ in the arm of the flesh; for I know that cursed is he that puts his trust in the arm of the flesh.",
    "answer": "Trust"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep4:35",
    "question": "I know that _____will give liberally to him that asks.",
    "answer": "God"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said “I will cry unto thee, my God, the rock of my righteousness”. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep4:35"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers said that they had much affliction because of Nephi’s words.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep5:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi’s brothers began to _____ against him and blame their trials because of him. (a) curse (b) murmur or (c) cry-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep5:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:3",
    "question": "Who thought that they should be the rulers of the people because they were older?",
    "answer": ["Laman", "Lemuel"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote all the words which his brothers murmured against him. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "2Nep5:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:5",
    "question": "Who warned Nephi to depart from his brothers and flee into the wilderness?",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi fled into the wilderness with his family and also with the families of Sam and _____. (a) Zoram (b) Jacob or (c) Joseph- (A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep5:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi had sisters; how many? (a) 3 (b) 4 or (c) we don’t know-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep5:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:6",
    "question": "All those that believed in the warnings and _____ or God; also fled with Nephi, into the wilderness.",
    "answer": "Revelations"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:8",
    "question": "What is the name of the place that the people gave to the place where they pitched their tents after fleeing from Nephi’s brother’s?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What name did the people give themselves after fleeing from Nephi’s brothers? (a) Nephites (b) the people of Nephi or (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep5:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:11",
    "question": "Nephi’s people began to raise _____, and herds, and animals of every kind.",
    "answer": "Flocks"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:12",
    "question": "Nephi had the plates of brass; and also the ball, or _____, which was prepared by the hand of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Compass"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:14",
    "question": "Nephi took the sword of _____, and after the manner of it did make many swords.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lamanites were first given that name in which book? (a) 1Nephi (b) 2Nephi or (c) 3Nephi-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep5:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi taught his people to build buildings, and to work in all manner of word, iron, and of copper. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep5:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:16",
    "question": "Nephi did build a temple; and constructed it after the manner of the temple of _____.",
    "answer": "Solomon"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s temple was build like Solomon’s and it also had all manner of precious things. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": "2Nep5:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The workmanship of the temple that Nephi built was exceedingly fine. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep5:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:18",
    "question": "Nephi’s people desired that he should be their _____, but he was desirous that there should be no king.",
    "answer": "King"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The words of the Lord were fulfilled when he spoke that Nephi should be the ruler over his brethren. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep5 19"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:20",
    "question": "What two brothers of Nephi were cut off from the presence of the Lord because they would not hearken to his words?",
    "answer": ["Laman", "Lemuel"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord caused that a cursing to come upon Laman and Lemuel and their families. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep5:21"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What color was the skin of Laman and Lemuel before they were cursed? (a) White (b) Brown or (c) Black-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep5:21"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:21",
    "question": "The Lord God did cause a skin of _____ to come upon Laman and Lemuel and their families.",
    "answer": "Blackness"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord said: Cursed shall be the seed of him that mixes with the seed of Laman and Lemuel. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep5:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the cursing that was upon them the Lamanites did become an idle people, full or mischief and subtlety. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep5:24"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep5:26",
    "question": "Nephi did consecrate Jacob and Joseph, that they should be priests and _____ over the land of his people.",
    "answer": "Teachers"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was obedient to the Lord and made another set of plates which contain the ministry of his people. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep5:30 & 1Nep9:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many years had passed away when Nephi and his people started to have wars and contentions with his brother’s people? (a) 30 (b) 40 or (c) 50-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep5:34"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:1",
    "question": "In chapter six of the Book of 2Nephi; Jacob recounts the history of what tribe of people?",
    "answer": "Jews"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:2",
    "question": "_____ was called of God, and ordained after the manner of his holy order, and consecrated by Nephi.",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob spoke to his people and was desirous for the welfare of their souls. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep6:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:3",
    "question": "Jacob spoke unto his people concerning all things which are written, from the creation of the _____.",
    "answer": "World"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:4",
    "question": "Jacob spoke to the Nephites for their sakes, that they would learn and glorify the name of their _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:4",
    "question": "Jacob read to his people the words of what Old Testament prophet?- ",
    "answer": "Isaiah"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who said, “I would speak unto you concerning things which are, and which are to come”. (a) Nephi (b) Jacob or (c) Lehi-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep6:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "There are many things which can be likened unto the Nephites because they are from the house of Israel. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep6:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:6",
    "question": "Who will lift up his hand to the Gentiles, and set up his standard to the people?",
    "answer": ["Lord", "God"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:7",
    "question": "Kings shall be thy nursing fathers’ and their _____ thy nursing mothers.",
    "answer": "Queens"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord showed Jacob those who were in Jerusalem and those that had been _____ and carried away captive. (a) hanged (b) slain or (c) trampled.-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep6:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:9",
    "question": "God, the Holy One of Israel, would manifest himself unto them in the flesh and they will scourge and crucify him.",
    "answer": "Israelites"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob saw the crucifixion or the Savior. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep6:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:10",
    "question": "After the Israelites hardened their hearts and _____ their necks against the Holy One of Israel his, judgments will come upon them.",
    "answer": "Stiffened"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said “the day comes that the Israelites shall be smitten and afflicted”. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep6:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who did the angel refer to when he said:  They shall be afflicted in the flesh, and shall not be suffered to perish, because of the prayers of the faithful? (a) Nephites. (b) Israelites or (c) Lamanites-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep6:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:11",
    "question": "The angel said: They shall be scattered, and smitten, and _____; nevertheless, the Lord will be merciful unto them.",
    "answer": "Hated"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:11",
    "question": "Who will come to the lands of their inheritance, after they come to the knowledge of their Redeemer?",
    "answer": "Israelites"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What people will be blessed, if they repent and fight not against Zion? (a) Gentiles (b) Israelites or (c) neither a nor b-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep6:12"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:13",
    "question": "Who are the covenant people of the Lord who are waiting for him and still waiting for the coming of the Messiah?",
    "answer": ["Jews", "Israelites"]
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:14",
    "question": "What people according to the words of the prophet? Will the Messiah set himself again the second time to recover them.",
    "answer": ["Jews", "Israelites"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Those that believe not him shall be destroyed, both by fire, and by tempest, and by earthquakes. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep6:15"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who will know that the Lord is God, the Holy One of Israel? (a) Lamanites (b) Unbelievers or (c) Nephites (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep6:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:17",
    "question": "For thus saith the Lord: “I will contend with them that _____ with thee.”",
    "answer": ["Contendeth", "Contends"]
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep6:18",
    "question": "All flesh shall know that I the Lord am thy _____ and thy Redeemer, the Mighty One of Jacob.",
    "answer": "Savior"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord said that those that oppress the Israelites; he will feed them with their own flesh.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep6:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep7:4",
    "question": "Who did the Lord give him a tongue of the learned, that he should know how to speak a word in season, to the house of Israel?- ",
    "answer": "Jacob"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep7:6",
    "question": " Who gave his back to the smiter, and his cheeks to them that plucked of his hair?",
    "answer": "Jesus Christ"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep7:9",
    "question": "They shall wax old as a garment, and the _____ shall eat them up?",
    "answer": "Moth"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep2:19",
    "question": "What ancient garden is mentioned in the Book Of Mormon",
    "answer": "Eden"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep8:3",
    "question": "Who will make her wilderness like Eden, and her desert like the garden of the Lord?- ",
    "answer": "Lord"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep8:3 & Alma19:14",
    "question": "Of all the national holidays that we celebrate in the United States of America; only _____ is mentioned in the Book of Mormon.",
    "answer": "Thanksgiving"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep8:15",
    "question": "But I am the Lord, thy God, whose waves roared; the Lord of _____ is my name.",
    "answer": "Hosts"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob spoke to his people so that they would rejoice and lift up their heads forever because of the blessings of God. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep9:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:4",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites that their flesh must waste away; nevertheless, in their bodies they shall see _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The creator died for all men, that all men might become subject unto him.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep9:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "It behooves the great creator that he suffers himself to become subject unto man in the _____. (a) night (b) flesh or (c) day-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep9:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Wherefore, it must needs be; an infinite atonement.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:8",
    "question": "For behold, if the flesh should rise no more our spirits must become subject the _____. ",
    "answer": "Devil "
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In 2Nephi- the devil is describe as an angel by Jacob.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:9",
    "question": "Who beguiled our first parents?-The ",
    "answer": "Devil "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:9",
    "question": "Who has the ability to transform himself as an angel of light?- ",
    "answer": "Devil "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:9",
    "question": "He stirs up the children of men unto secret combinations of murder and all manner of secret works of _____.-",
    "answer": "Darkness "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob called the death of the body, and the death of the spirit, as a monster.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "  2Nep9: 10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob spoke and liken; spiritual death as hell.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "  2Nep9:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:11",
    "question": "What kind of death shall deliver up its dead; which death is the grave?",
    "answer": "Temporal "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "It is by the power of God, that the bodies and the spirits of men will be restored one to the other.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:13",
    "question": "The paradise of God must deliver up the spirits of the _____ and the grave deliver up the body of the righteous.",
    "answer": "Righteous "
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep9:14",
    "question": "When we die; we shall have a perfect knowledge of our guilt, and our uncleanness.",
    "answer": "T"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:15",
    "question": "After we die, we must appear before the judgment _____ of the Holy One or Israel.",
    "answer": "Seat "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:16",
    "question": "Those who are righteous shall be righteous still, and they who are filthy shall be _____ still.",
    "answer": "Filthy "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:16",
    "question": "They who are filthy are the devil and his _____.",
    "answer": "Angels "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:16",
    "question": "The devils everlasting torment is as a lake of fire and _____.-",
    "answer": "Brimstone "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The devil’s lake has a flame that ascends up forever and ever and has no end.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "God executes all his words from his mouth, and his law must be _____. (a) fulfilled (b) false or (c) correct-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep9:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:19",
    "question": "The lake of fire and brimstone can be describe; as _____ torment.- ",
    "answer": "Everlasting "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "God knows all things, and there is not anything save he knows it.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:21",
    "question": "Jesus Christ has suffered the pains of all men, the pains of every living creature, both men_____, and children.",
    "answer": "Women "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:23",
    "question": "He commands all men, that they must repent, and be _____ in his name, having perfect faith in the Holy One of Israel-.",
    "answer": "Baptized "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:24",
    "question": "Those that don’t repent and believe in his name, and _____ to the end, must be damned.",
    "answer": "Endure "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Wherefore, he has given a law; and where there is no law given there is no _____.  (a) mercy (b) punishment or (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep9:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:26",
    "question": "For the _____ satisfies the demands of his justice upon all of those who have not the law given to them.",
    "answer": "Atonement "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:27",
    "question": "Woe to those that transgress the laws of God, and that waste the days of his _____for awful is state.",
    "answer": "Probation "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Men when they are learned, think they are wise, and they hearken not unto the counsel of God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "  2Nep9:28"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:29",
    "question": "But to be_____ is good if they hearken unto the counsels of God.-",
    "answer": "Learned "
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:30",
    "question": "Woe unto the rich, who are _____ as to the things of this world.-",
    "answer": "Rich "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The rich love their treasures, and their treasures is their _____ (a) fault (b) God or (c) downfall-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep9:30"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Woe unto the murderer who deliberately kills, for he shall die.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "  2Nep9:35"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:37",
    "question": "Yea, woe unto those that worship idols, for the _____ of all devils delights in them.",
    "answer": "Devil "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:39",
    "question": "Remember, to be carnally-minded is death, and to be _____-minded is life eternal.",
    "answer": "Spiritually "
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Another name for the Savior is_____. (a) baker (b) shaker or (c) Maker-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1Nep9:40"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The righteous love the truth and were not shaken by Jacob’s words.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:40"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:41",
    "question": "Who is the keeper of the gate of heaven?- ",
    "answer": "Lord "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord, who is the keeper of the gate of heaven employs a servant/servants there. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:41"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "There is no other way to get to heaven; we must all enter through the gate of heaven.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:41"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "God despises those that are puffed up because of their learning and their wisdom, and their riches.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:42"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:44",
    "question": "Jacob prayed to his God of salvation that he might view him with his all-_____ eye.",
    "answer": "Searching "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wanted his people to come to God, who is the rock of their salvation. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:45"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:48",
    "question": "The Nephites looked up to Jacob as a _____, and it was expedient that he teach them the consequences of sin.",
    "answer": "Teacher "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob’s soul abhors sin, and his heart delights in righteousness. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:49"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep9:52",
    "question": "Remember the words of your God; pray unto him continually by day, and give thanks unto his holy name by _____.- ",
    "answer": "Night "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Future generations of Jacob’s seed shall become a righteous branch unto the house of Israel.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep9:53"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:3",
    "question": "Jacob was told that the Savior’s name would be _____ by an angel of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Christ "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Christ would come to those that were in the more wicked part of the world.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "  2Nep10:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Because of their _____ and iniquities, they at Jerusalem will stiffen their necks and crucify him.  (a) priest-crafts (b) lies or (c) dumbness-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep10:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:8",
    "question": "The Jews he will gather from their long dispersion, from the isles of the sea, and from the _____ of the earth.",
    "answer": "Parts "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The kings of the Gentiles shall be nursing fathers unto them.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep10:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The land shall be a land of liberty unto the Gentiles and they shall be blessed. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep10:10-11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And he that fights against Zion shall perish, says God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep10:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:15",
    "question": "The Lord must needs to destroy the secret work of darkness, and of murders, and of _____.",
    "answer": "Abominations "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:16",
    "question": "For they who are not for me are _____ me, saith our God.",
    "answer": "Against "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:18",
    "question": "The Lord will afflict the seed of Jacob by the hand of the _____.- ",
    "answer": "Gentiles "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren; remember that ye are free to act for yourselves. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep10:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:23",
    "question": "We are free to choose the way of everlasting death or the way of eternal _____.",
    "answer": "Life "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:24",
    "question": "It is only through the _____ of God that we are saved.",
    "answer": "Grace "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep10:25",
    "question": "Wherefore, may God raise you from death by the power of the resurrection, and also from everlasting death by the power of the _____.",
    "answer": "Atonement "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote all the things that Jacob spoke to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep11:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote more of the words of Isaiah, for my soul delights in his words.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep11:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep11:2",
    "question": "Nephi liken the words of _____ unto his people, and he would send them forth unto all his children.",
    "answer": "Isaiah "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi both saw the Savior.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep11:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep11:3",
    "question": "Wherefore, by the words of _____, God hath said, I will establish my word.",
    "answer": "Three "
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nevertheless, God will send more witnesses, to prove that his words are true. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep11:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many more witnesses did the Lord say he would send?_____(a) 6 (b) 8 (c) 10-(B) 2Nep11:3, Refer to the Testimonyof",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Eight Witnesses"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep11:4",
    "question": "By the coming of Christ; the law of _____ will come to an end.-",
    "answer": "Moses "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s soul delights in proving unto his people that if Christ had not come, all men must of, perished.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep11:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep11:7",
    "question": "For if there be no Christ there be no God; and if there be no God we are not, for there could have been no _____.-",
    "answer": "Creation "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep11:7",
    "question": "Nephi said that Christ would come in the _____ of his own time.- ",
    "answer": "Fulness "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote some of the words of Isaiah, that his people would liken his words to themselves as well as us in our time.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep11:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep12:1",
    "question": "The father of Isaiah the prophet was _____.-",
    "answer": "Amoz "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep12:2",
    "question": "The house of the Lord shall be established in the top of the mountains, and all shall be exalted above the hills, and all nations shall ____ unto it.-",
    "answer": "Flow "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "O Lord, thou hast forsaken the house of Jacob, because they were replenished from the east, and hearken unto soothsayers like the Philistines.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep12:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep12:12",
    "question": "For the day of the Lord of _____soon comes upon all nations.-",
    "answer": "Hosts "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep12:13",
    "question": "Yea, the day of the Lord shall come upon all the _____ of Lebanon, for they are lifted up; and upon all the oaks of Bashan.",
    "answer": "Cedars "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep12:19",
    "question": "And they shall hide themselves into the holes of the rocks, and into the _____ of the earth, for the fear of the Lord.",
    "answer": "Caves "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep13:4",
    "question": "And the Lord said- “I will give children unto them to be their princes, and _____ shall rule over them”. ",
    "answer": "Babes "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote about the countenance of the people and declared their sin to be even as the city of Sodom.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep13:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi said that there should be a _____ for a shadow in the daytime from the heat, and for a place of refuge.  (a) building (b) tabernacle or (c) barn-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep14:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because the daughters of Zion are haughty, and walk with stretched-forth necks and wanton eyes, the Lord will smite them with a scab on the crown of their heads.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep13:16-17"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep15:4",
    "question": "The Lord looked at his vineyard that it might bring forth grapes, but instead it brought forth _____ grapes.-",
    "answer": "Wild "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For the vineyard of the Lord or Hosts is the house of Israel.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep15:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The men of Judah are the Lord of Host’s pleasant_____. (a) plant (b) apple or (c) orange-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep15:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord of Hosts has said that many houses shall be desolate, and great and fair cities without inhabitant.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep15:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep15:26",
    "question": "The Lord will lift up an_____ to the nations from afar, and will hiss unto them from the end of the earth.-",
    "answer": "Ensign "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In what king’s reign did Isaiah see the Lord of Hosts sitting upon a throne, high and lifted up? (a) Uzziah (b) King Tut or (c) neither a nor b-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep16:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "When Isaiah saw the Seraphim creature, how many wings did the Seraphim creature have? (a) two (b) six (c) one-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep16:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep16:5",
    "question": "Isaiah said that his eyes had seen the King, the Lord of _____. ",
    "answer": "Hosts "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep16:8",
    "question": "The Lord asked: “Whom should I send to warn the people”? And Isaiah said, here I am, _____ me. ",
    "answer": "Send "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "King Ahaz made an alliance with the king of Assryria, in order to repel an attack from Syria and Israel.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep17:1 and Isaiah 7"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "For the head of Syria is _____. (a) bad (b) smelly or (c) Damascus-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep17:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Ahaz did not ask or temp the Lord for a sign.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep17:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep17:14",
    "question": "Jacob said the Lord will show the people a sign: which was a _____ and she shall conceive, and shall bear a son, and his name will be Immauel.",
    "answer": "Virgin "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord has sent his word unto _____ and it he has lighted it upon Israel.  (a) Laman (b) Lemuel or (c)-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Isaiah2Nep18:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Isaiah took Uriah the priest and Zechariah the son of Jeberechiah to record and witness the birth of Maher-shalal-hash-baz.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep18:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Maher-shalal-hash-baz is the name of_____son. (a) Nephi's  (b) Isaiah's or (c) Zarahemla's-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep18:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord shall be a sanctuary to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep18:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob asked; should not a people seek unto their God for the living to hear from the dead? ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep18:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And those that speak not according to his word; it is because there is no light from God in them.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep18:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep19:6",
    "question": "Another name for Jesus Christ is The Prince of _____.",
    "answer": "Peace "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord refers to himself as The Everlasting Father.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep19:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep19:8",
    "question": "The Lord sent his word unto Jacob and he has lighted it upon the house of _____.",
    "answer": "Israel "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep19:12",
    "question": "For all the Lord’s anger against Israel is not turned away, but his hand is _____ out still.",
    "answer": "Stretched "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord has smitten the house of Israel, but they continue not to turn to him or seek him.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep19:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The leaders of the people cause them to err; and they that are led of them are destroyed.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep19:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep19:21",
    "question": "Ephraim and _____ will join together and be against Judah.",
    "answer": "Manasseh "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And though the people of Israel shall be as the sand of the sea, a remnant of them shall return.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep20:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep21:7",
    "question": "Jacob prophesied that in the end of times; the lion shall eat straw like the _____.",
    "answer": "Ox "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "There shall be a root of Jesse which shall stand for an ensign of the people.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep21:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord shall utterly destroy the tongue of the _____ Sea. (a) Red (b) Egyptian or (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep21:15"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep22:2",
    "question": "God is my salvation; I will trust, and not be afraid; the Lord_____ is my strength and my song.",
    "answer": "Jehovah "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep23:19",
    "question": "Jacob said that Babylon, the beauty of the Chaldees’ excellency, shall be as when God overthrew Sodom and _____.",
    "answer": "Gomorrah "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord will have mercy on the Jacob and shall take them captives unto whom they were captives and rule over their oppressors.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep24:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep24:12",
    "question": "How art thou fallen from heaven, O Lucifer, son of the _____ ",
    "answer": "Morning "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many times does the name Lucifer appear in the Book Of Mormon?_____-(a) 1 (b) 2 or (c) 3",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep24:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep24:12",
    "question": "The word Lucifer only appears in the Book of Mormon once, name the Book in which it appears in. ",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep24:13",
    "question": "Lucifer wanted to ascend into heaven, and wanted to exalt his throne above the stars of _____.",
    "answer": "God "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord of Hosts hath sworn, saying: “Surely as I have thought, so shall it come to pass: and as I have purposed, so shall it stand”-",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep24:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:2",
    "question": "Nephi did not teach his people all the things concerning the manner of the Jews, because their works were works of _____, and their doings were doings of abominations.",
    "answer": "Darkness "
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that Isaiah spoke many things which were hard for his people to understand.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep25:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s plainness started when he left Jerusalem and his soul delighteth in plainness unto his people that they may learn. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep25:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s soul delighted in the words of Isaiah.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep25:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that he beheld the things of the Jewish people; and that they knew and understood the words of the prophets spoken to them. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep25:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi proceeded with his own prophecies in plainness that he knew that no man can err. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep25:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:7",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that in the days that the prophecies of Isaiah shall be fulfilled, men shall know of a surety, at the times when they shall come to _____. ",
    "answer": "Pass "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that never have any of the Jews been destroyed without warning save it were foretold them by the prophets of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep25:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:12",
    "question": "Nephi refers to the Savior as the Only_____of the Father.",
    "answer": "Begotten"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many days did Nephi say the Lord would be laid in sepulchre before he shall rise?_____(a) 1 (b) 2 or (c) 3-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep25:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s soul delights to prophesy concerning Jesus Christ, for he had seen his day and his heart did magnify his holy name.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep25:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that after the Messiah has risen from the dead, and has manifested himself unto his people, _____ shall be destroyed again.  (a) Salt Lake City (b) Sugar City or (c) Jerusalem-Jerusalem",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep25:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:18",
    "question": "Nephi said there is save one Messiah spoken by the prophets, and that Messiah is he who should be rejected of the _____.",
    "answer": "Jews "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:19",
    "question": "Who is the first person in the Book of Mormon to refer to the Savior by the name of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:19",
    "question": "According to the words of the prophets, and also the word of the angel of God, his name shall be_____ _____, the Son of God.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:20",
    "question": "The Lord gave power unto _____ that he should heal nations after they had been bittern by poisonous serpents; if they would cast their eyes unto the serpent.",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi said there is no other name given under _____ save it be this Jesus Christ, of which I have spoken, whereby man can be saved.  (a) the stars (b) heaven (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep25:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:21",
    "question": "The Lord God promised unto _____ that the things which I write shall be kept and preserved, and handed down unto his seed.",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord God promised unto Joseph, that his seed should never perish as long as the earth should stand.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep25:21"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:23",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob labored diligently to write, to persuade their children and their brethren, to believe in Christ, and to be reconciled to _____.",
    "answer": "God"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:24",
    "question": "The Nephites kept the law of _____, and looked forward with steadfastness unto Christ, until the law would be fulfilled. ",
    "answer": "Moses"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that after Christ should come, the law of Moses would be dead; and they were made alive in Christ because of their faith.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep25:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:26",
    "question": "Nephi said, “we talk of Christ, we rejoice in Christ, we preach of Christ, we prophesy of _____.”",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:26",
    "question": "Who did Nephi say that his children and his brethren should know to what source they may look for a remission of their sins? ",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The words which Nephi has spoken shall stand as a testimony against his people, and they are sufficient to teach any man the right way.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep25:28"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:29",
    "question": "And now behold, I say unto you that the right way is to believe in _____, and deny him not, and he is the Holy One of Israel.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep25:29",
    "question": "Wherefore ye must bow down before him, and worship him with all your ____, mind, and strength, and your soul.",
    "answer": "Might"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that after Christ shall have risen from the dead he would show himself unto the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:2",
    "question": "Nephi saw many generations pass away, and there would be great _____ and contentions among his people.",
    "answer": "Wars"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that after the Messiah shall come there shall be signs given unto his people of his birth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:3",
    "question": "Unto the Nephites there shall be given signs of the Messiah’s death and _____.",
    "answer": "Resurrection"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:3",
    "question": "The wicked perish because they cast out the _____, and the saints, and stone and slay them.",
    "answer": "Prophets"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because the wicked do bad things; the blood of the saints shall ascend up to God from the ground against them.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Those that are proud and wicked, the Lord will burn as _____.   (a) stubble (b) to the ground or (c) he pleases-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep26:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The wicked shall be visited with thundering, lightning, and earthquakes, and all manner of destruction.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The righteous look forward unto Christ with steadfastness for the signs which are given, not withstanding all persecution-. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Son of righteousness shall appear unto the Nephites and he shall heal them.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:9",
    "question": "How many generations will have pass away in righteousness after the Savior appears unto the Nephites? ",
    "answer": "3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Nephites will reap destruction, because of their pride and foolishness.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:10",
    "question": "Because the Nephites yielded unto the _____ and choose works of darkness rather than light, therefore they must go down to hell.",
    "answer": "Devil"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:11",
    "question": "Nephi wrote- The _____ of the Lord will not always strive with man. ",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that when the spirit of the Lord ceases to strive with man, then comes speedy destruction.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:12",
    "question": "Not only do the Jews need to be convinced that Jesus is the very Christ, it must needs be that the _____ be convinced also that Jesus is the Christ, the Eternal God.",
    "answer": "Gentiles"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:12",
    "question": "Who was the first person in the Book of Mormon to call the Savior by the name of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "Nephi"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:13",
    "question": "Jesus Christ manifest's himself unto all those that believe in him by the power of the Holy _____.",
    "answer": "Ghost"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:13",
    "question": "According to the faith among the children of men, God will work mighty _____, signs, and wonders.",
    "answer": "Miracles"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi prophesied concerning the last days; concerning the days that the Lord God shall bring mighty things forth unto the children of men.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:16",
    "question": "For those who shall be destroyed shall speak unto them out of the ground, and their speech shall be low out of the _____.",
    "answer": "Dust"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "It shall come to pass, that those who have dwindled in unbelief shall be _____ by the hands of the Gentiles.  (a) slapped (b) smitten or (c) led-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep26:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:20",
    "question": "The Gentiles are lifted up in the _____ of their eyes, and have stumbled.",
    "answer": "Pride"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the greatness of their stumbling blocks, the Gentiles have built up many churches.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:20",
    "question": "The Gentiles put down the power and miracles of _____. ",
    "answer": "God"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:20",
    "question": "The Gentiles preach up unto themselves their own wisdom and _____; that they may get gain and grind upon the face of the poor.",
    "answer": "Learning"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "There are many churches built up which cause envyings, and strifes, and malice.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:21"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:22",
    "question": "The Gentiles are also into _____ combinations, even as in times of old.",
    "answer": "Secret"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:22",
    "question": "Who is the foundation of evil things and works of darkness? The ",
    "answer": "Devil-  "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The devil leads men by the neck with a _____ cord, until he binds them with his strong cords forever.  (a) stiff (b) flaxen or (c) tough-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep26:22"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote: “For behold, my beloved brethren, I say unto you that the Lord God works not in darkness”.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Nep26:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord does not do anything but for the benefit of man and the world.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord loves the world; even that he lays down his own life that he may draw all men unto him.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Wherefore, the Lord commands all men to partake of his salvation.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord has given all men the opportunity to partake of his salvation for free.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said the Lord does not cry unto any, saying: “Depart from me”.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord has given his salvation free for all men; and he commanded his people that they should persuade all men to repentance.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:27"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord has commanded that there should be no priestcrafts.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:29"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:29",
    "question": "What is the name of the things that men preach and set themselves up for a light unto the world? ",
    "answer": "Priestcrafts"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Men do priestcrafts to get gain and praise of the world; but they seek not the welfare of Zion.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:29"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:30",
    "question": "The Lord God has given a commandment that all men should have _____, which charity is love.",
    "answer": "Charity"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord God has said that if we do not have charity we are nothing.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:30"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that the laborer in Zion shall labor fro Zion; for if they labor for money they shall perish.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:31"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi recited the Ten Commandments in 2Nephi.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:32"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "No iniquities come of the Lord; for he does that which is _____ among the children of men.  (a) good (b) tasteful or (c) awful-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep26:33"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:33",
    "question": "The Lord does nothing save it be plain unto the children of men; and he invites them all to come unto him and partake of his _____.",
    "answer": "Goodness- "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep26:33",
    "question": "The Lord denies none that come unto him, black and white, bond and free, _____ and female.",
    "answer": "Male"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord remembers the heathen, and all are alike unto God, both Jew and Gentile.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep26:33"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi prophesied that in the days of the Gentiles; all nations of the Gentiles and of the Jews they will be drunken with iniquity and all manner of abominations",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In those days of the Gentiles; the Lord will visit them with storm, tempest, and earthquakes, and with the flame of devouring fire.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For behold, all those that do iniquity; you shall be drunken but not with wine, you shall stagger but not from strong drink.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:6",
    "question": "Nephi said: 'It shall come to pass that the Lord shall bring forth unto you the words of a book, and they shall be the _____ of them which have slumbered'.",
    "answer": "Words"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The book that the Lord shall deliver will be sealed up; and in the book shall be a revelation from God, from the beginning of the world to the ending thereof.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "But the book shall be delivered unto a man, and he shall deliver the words of the _____.  (a) Lamanites (b) book or (c) 2nd coming-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep27:9"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that the man would not deliver the words of the book which are sealed by the power of God. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "When will the revelation/revelations of the book be delivered or made known to us? (a) 2025 (b) the Lords own due time or (c) when we are worthy -(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep27:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:10",
    "question": "The portion of the book which is sealed reveals all things from the foundation of the _____ unto the end thereof.",
    "answer": "World"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:11",
    "question": "And the day will come that the words of the book which were sealed shall be read upon the _____ tops; and they shall be read by the power of Christ.",
    "answer": "House"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:12",
    "question": "None shall behold the book, save it be that _____ witnesses shall behold it, by the power of God, besides him to whom the book shall be delivered.",
    "answer": "Three"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Those to whom the book shall be delivered shall testify to the truth of the book and the things therein.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord God shall say unto him whom he shall deliver the book:  Take these words which are not sealed and deliver them to another, that he may show them unto the _____ man.  (a) learned (b) nosey or (c) neither a nor b-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep27:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And the learned shall say:  Bring hither the book, and I will read it.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because the learned will try to get gain and the glory of the world and not for God, he will not be able to read the sealed portion of the book.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:16-17"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord will deliver again the book and the words thereof to him that is not learned and he shall say:  “I am not learned”.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:21",
    "question": "Touch not the things which are _____; for I will show unto the children of men that I am able to do mine own work.",
    "answer": "Sealed"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord shall see fit in his own wisdom to reveal all things unto the children of men.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:23",
    "question": "For behold, I am God; and I am a God of miracles; and I will show unto the world that I am the same, yesterday, _____, and forever.",
    "answer": "Today"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord will not work among the children of men save it be according to their _____.  (a) obedience (b) usefulness or (c) faith-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep27:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:26",
    "question": "Therefore, I will proceed to do a marvelous work and a _____, among the people.",
    "answer": "Wonder"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Woe unto them that seek deep to hide their counsel from the Lord! And their works are in the dark.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "But behold, I will show unto them, saith the Lord of Hosts, that I know all their works.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep27:29",
    "question": "There will come a day that the deaf shall hear the words of the book and the eyes of the blind shall see out of obscurity and out of _____.",
    "answer": "Darkness- "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The poor among the people will rejoice in the Holy One of Israel.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:30"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "For assuredly as the Lord lives they shall see that the terrible one is brought to _____. (a) his knees (b) naught or (c) something-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep27:31"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Neither be ashamed neither your face wax pale, says the Lord, who redeemed Abraham, to the house of _____.  (a) Nephi (b) Jacob or (c) Lehi-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep27:33"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that those that erred in spirit shall come to understanding, and they that murmured shall learn doctrine.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep27:35"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi spoke unto his people, according as the Spirit had constrained him.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The things written out of the book; shall be of great worth unto the _____of men.  (a) power (b) children or (c) learning-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep28:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The things that are written in the book will be worth especially more unto the seed of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep28:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The seed of Nephi is a remnant of the house of Israel. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "A lot of churches will say: I am the Lord’s but not all of them will be built up unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In the last days a lot of churches will contend one with another and so will their _____.  (a) priests (b) angels or (c) neither a nor b-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep28:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:4",
    "question": "Churches will teach with their learning, and deny the Holy _____ which gives utterance.",
    "answer": "Ghost"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "A lot of churches deny the power of God, the Holy One of Israel.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Churches will say: Hearken unto us, and hear our precept; for behold there is no God today.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "A lot of churches will say that the Lord the Redeemer has done his work, and he has given his power unto men.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In the last days churches will say that the Lord God has done away with miracles because he already has done his work.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:7",
    "question": "Yea, there shall be many which say:  Eat, drink and be _____, for tomorrow we die; and it shall be well with us.",
    "answer": "Merry"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Eat, drink, and be merry; nevertheless, fear God-he will justify in committing a little sin.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep28:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:8",
    "question": "Many will say-dig a pit for thy neighbor; there is no harm in this; for tomorrow we _____. ",
    "answer": "Die"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:8",
    "question": "If we are guilty of doing bad things many will say: God will beat us with a few _____, and at last we shall be saved in the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Stripes- "
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Many churches shall teach false and vain and foolish doctrines.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Many will seek to hide their counsels from the Lord; and their works shall be in the dark.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The blood of the saints, shall cry from the _____ against false churches.  (a) wells (b) ground or (c) sky-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep28:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of pride, and because of false doctrine, their churches have become corrupted.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:12"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Many churches are lifted up because of pride and they are _____ up.  (a) puffed (b) filthy or (c) lifted-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep28:12"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of their fine sanctuaries and clothing; many churches rob the poor.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:13",
    "question": "Because of their pride, many churches _____ the meek and the poor in heart.",
    "answer": "Persecute"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Many churches because of wickedness and abominations; have gone astray save it be a few, who are the humble followers of Christ.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:4",
    "question": "Churches are led, that in many instances they do err because they are taught by the learning of _____.",
    "answer": "Men"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "O the wise, and the learned, and the rich, that are puffed up in the pride of their hearts; they shall be thrust down to hell.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:15"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:15",
    "question": "Woe, woe, _____ be unto them, saith the Lord God Almighty, for they shall be thrust down to hell.",
    "answer": "Woe"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For the day shall come that the Lord will speedily visit the inhabitants of the earth; and in that day those who are fully ripe in iniquity shall perish.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Those that repent of their wickedness and _____, they shall not be destroyed, saith the Lord of Hosts.  (a) abominations (b) sins or (c) filthiness-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep28:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:18",
    "question": "The great and _____ church shall tumble to the earth, and great must be the fall thereof.",
    "answer": "Abominable"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "It shall come to pass that the _____ of the devil shall shake.  (a) pit (b) kingdom or (c) earth-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep28:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In the last days the devil shall rage in the hearts of the children of men.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "  2Nep28:20"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The devil will stir up the children of men, and stir them up to anger against that which is good.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:21",
    "question": "Carnal-",
    "answer": "The devil will pacify, and lull many of the people to _____ security.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:21",
    "question": "Zion- ",
    "answer": "Many will say:  All is well in _____; yea, Zion prospers, all is well.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep28:21",
    "question": "The devil cheats many men of their souls, and leads them carefully down to hell.",
    "answer": "T"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:22",
    "question": "Devil-",
    "answer": "The devil flatters away many, and tells them there is no hell; and says unto them:  I am no _____, for there is none.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The devil whispers into people’s ear, until he grasps them with his awful chains, from where there is no deliverance.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And all that have been seized by the devil must stand before the throne of God, and be judged according to their works. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The wicked will go to the place prepared for them, even if it is a lake of fire and brimstone. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Another way to best describe the lake of fire and brimstone is endless torment.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:23"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said therefore, woe be unto him that is at ease in Zion!",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote:” Woe be unto him that cries all is well! Even all is well in Zion”.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:26",
    "question": "Men-",
    "answer": "Woe be unto him that hearkens unto the precepts of _____, and denies the power of God, and the gift of the Holy Ghost!  "
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For behold, he that is built upon the rock receives the word of God with gladness; and he that is built upon a sandy foundation trembles and he shall fall.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep28:28"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:29",
    "question": "Word-",
    "answer": "Woe be unto him that shall say:  We have received the _____ of God, and we need no more of the word of God, for we have enough. "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:3”",
    "question": "Precept-",
    "answer": "For behold, thus saith the Lord God “I will give unto the children of men line upon line, precept upon “_____.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep28:30",
    "question": "Little-",
    "answer": "The Lord gives his word, here a little and there a _____; and blessed are those who hearken unto my precepts. "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord is pleased with us when we lend and ear unto his counsel, and he has said that we will learn wisdom because of it.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:30"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For those that say:  We have enough, from them shall be taken away even that which they already have.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:30"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote: Cursed is he that puts his trust in man, or makes flesh his arm.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:31"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Woe be unto the _____, I will be merciful unto them, saith the Lord God, if they will repent and come unto me.  (a) ugly (b) Zoramites or (c) Gentiles-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep28:32"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord has said unto the Gentiles:  Repent and come unto me; for mine arm is lengthened out all day long for you.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep28:32"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi prophesied that the Lord will set his hand a second time to recover his people, which are of the house of Israel. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep29:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:2",
    "question": "Lehi-",
    "answer": "The Lord promised to remember the covenants he made to Nephi and his father named _____.  "
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord’s words shall proceed forth out of his mouth unto the seed of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep29:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "God’s words shall hiss forth unto the ends of the earth, for a _____ unto my people, which are of the house of Israel.  (a) proclamation (b) standard or (c) lecture-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep29:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:3",
    "question": "Bible-",
    "answer": "Many Gentiles shall say:  A Bible! A _____! We have got a Bible, and there cannot be any more Bible.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who are the Lords ancient covenant people? (a) Louisianan  (b) Idahoan or (c) Jews or (c)-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep29:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "2Nep29:5",
    "question": "The Gentiles have not remembered the Lord’s covenant people, but have cursed and hated them, and have not sought to recover them.",
    "answer": "T"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Those that say:  A Bible, we have got a Bible, and we need no more Bible, they are _____, the Lord has said.  (a) not smart (b) not Christians or (c) fools-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep29:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord asked: “Know ye not that there are more nations than one”?  Know ye not that I, the Lord your God, have created all men.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep29:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "God remembers every single one of us, even those that are upon the isles of the sea.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep29:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:7",
    "question": "Rules-",
    "answer": "The Lord _____ in the heavens above and in the earth beneath.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "God will bring forth his word unto the children of men, yea, even upon all the nations of the earth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep29:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:8",
    "question": "Murmur-",
    "answer": "Wherefore _____ ye, because that ye shall receive more of my word?  "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord said:  “Know ye not that the testimony of _____ nations is a witness unto you that I am God, and that I remember one nation like unto another”.   (a) two (b) twenty or (c) four-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Nep29:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:8",
    "question": "Testimony-",
    "answer": "And when the two nations shall run together the _____ of the two nations shall run together also.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The testimony of the two nations will prove unto many that God is the same yesterday, today, and forever.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep29:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord’s work is not yet finished; neither shall it be until the end of _____, neither from that time henceforth and forever.  (a) time (b) man or (c) the tonight show-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep29:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:10",
    "question": "Bible-",
    "answer": "Wherefore, because that ye have a _____ ye need not suppose that it contains all the Lord’s words.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Just because we have a Bible, we need not suppose that it contains all of the Lord’s words and that he has not caused more to be written.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep29:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:11",
    "question": "North-",
    "answer": "The Lord has commanded all men, both in the east and west, and in the _____, and in the south; that they should write which he has spoken unto them.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord has not commanded the people in the islands of the sea to write the words which he has spoken.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep29:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:11",
    "question": "Written-",
    "answer": "God will judge every man according to his works, and according to that which is _____.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord will speak unto the Jews and Nephites to write that which he has spoken.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep29:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:12",
    "question": "Tribes-",
    "answer": "The other _____ of the house of Israel that the Lord has led away; will also write the words which he has spoken.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:13",
    "question": "Jews-",
    "answer": "And it shall come to pass that the Jews shall have the words of the Nephites, and the Nephites shall have the words of the _____.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:13",
    "question": "Lost- ",
    "answer": "The Nephites and Jews shall have the words of the _____ tribes of Israel and the lost tribes of Israel shall have the words of the Nephites and Jews.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And it shall come to pass that my people; whom are of the house of Israel, shall be gathered home unto the lands of their possessions.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep29:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep29:14",
    "question": "Abraham-",
    "answer": "The Lord will show unto them that fight against his word and people that I am God, and that I covenanted with _____ and that I would remember his seed forever.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote:  I, Nephi, would suffer that ye should suppose that ye are more righteous than the Gentiles.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For behold, if we do not keep the commandments of God, we shall likewise perish.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the words that have been written, we should suppose that the Gentiles will be utterly destroyed.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:2",
    "question": "Jews-",
    "answer": "As many of the Gentiles as will repent are the covenant people of the Lord; and as many of the _____ as will not repent shall be cast off.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:2",
    "question": "Lord-",
    "answer": "The _____ has covenanted with none save it be with them that repent and believe in his Son, who is the Holy One of Israel.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "After the book shall come forth, and be written unto the Gentiles, and sealed up again unto the Lord, there shall be many which believe the words that are written.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:3",
    "question": "Gentiles-",
    "answer": "Who will carry forth the words which shall be written in the book unto the remnant seed of Nephi?_____"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:4",
    "question": "Jerusalem-",
    "answer": "Then shall the remnant of our seed know concerning the Nephites, how that we came out from _____, and that they are descendants of the Jews.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:5",
    "question": "Lemuel-",
    "answer": "The gospel of Jesus Christ shall be declared unto the remnant of the seed of Laman and _____.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:5",
    "question": "Lamanites-",
    "answer": "Who shall be restored unto the knowledge of their fathers, and also to the knowledge of Jesus Christ, which was had among their fathers? "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When the Lamanites come to the knowledge of their fathers, they will rejoice; for they shall know that it is a blessing unto them from the Lord.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:6",
    "question": "Lamanites-",
    "answer": "Whose scales of darkness shall begin to fall from their eyes when the gospel of Jesus Christ shall be declared among them, and they shall be restored unto the knowledge of their fathers?  The "
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Once there scales of darkness fall off, many generations shall not pass away among them, save they shall be a white and delightsome people",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:7",
    "question": "Pass-",
    "answer": "And it shall come to _____ that the Jews which are scattered also shall begin to believe in Jesus Christ that he is was the Messiah.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:7 ",
    "question": "Christ-",
    "answer": "Many Jews shall begin to gather in upon the face of the land; and as many as shall believe in _____ shall also become a delightsome people. "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:8",
    "question": "People-",
    "answer": "And it shall come to pass that the Lord God shall commence his work among all nations, tongues, and _____.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord will bring the restoration of the gospel to his people who are upon the earth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:9",
    "question": "Meek-",
    "answer": "And with righteousness shall the Lord God judge the poor, and reprove with equity the _____ of the earth.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:9",
    "question": "Wicked-",
    "answer": "The Lord will smite the earth with the rod of his mouth; and with the breath of his lips shall he slay the _____.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For the time speedily comes that the Lord God shall cause a great division among the people, and the wicked will he destroy.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord will spare the righteous and his people, yea, even if it so be that he must destroy the wicked by _____. (a) rockets (b) fire or (c) flooding the earth-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep30:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "And _____ shall be the girdle of his loins, and faithfulness the girdle of his reins.  (a) Gentiles (b) righteousness or (c) Lamanites-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep30:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "And the leopard shall lie down with the kid, and the calf, and the young lion together, and a _____ child shall lead them.  (a) little (b) smart or (c) big-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep30:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In the last days the cow and the bear shall feed together, and the lion shall eat _____ like the ox.  (a) straw (b) hay or (c) fruit-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep30:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The earth shall be full of the knowledge of the Lord, the same as the waters cover the sea.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:15"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In the last days – the things of all _____ shall be made known; yea, all things shall be known unto the children of men.  (a) cities (b) nations or (c) the universe-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep30:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In the last days not all the secret things will be revealed unto men.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said concerning the end that there will be no works of darkness save it shall be made manifest in the light.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Wherefore, all things which have been revealed unto the children of men shall not be revealed at that day.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep30:18",
    "question": "Hearts-",
    "answer": "Nephi wrote that Satan shall have no power over the _____ of the children of men, no more, for a long time.  "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How long did Nephi say that Satan would have no power over the children of men? (a) long time (b) 1,000 years or (c) a lot of years-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep30:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Never in the Book of Mormon are we told by Mormon how long Satan will be chained up for during the second coming of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep30:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi wrote but a few things which shall come to pass; neither could he write but of few words of his brother _____. (a) Sam (b) Jacob or (c) Laman-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep31:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi spoke plainly of the doctrine of Christ, as far as the plainness of his prophesying.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep31:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:3",
    "question": "Nephi wrote:  My soul _____ in plainness; for after this manner does the Lord God work among the children of men.",
    "answer": "Delight"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For the Lord God gives light unto all his words and works so that we can be confused.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep31:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:3",
    "question": "For the Lord speaks to each of us according to our _____, so that we can all understand him.",
    "answer": "Language"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:4",
    "question": "Nephi wrote and hoped that we should all remember the Lord and he showed him the _____ who would baptize the Lamb of God.",
    "answer": "Prophet"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Never in the Book of Mormon are we told by Mormon what the name of the prophet is who will baptize the Lamb of God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Neph31:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that the Lamb of God would take only the real bad sins away from all of us. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep31:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:5",
    "question": "If the Lamb of God should have need to be baptized by _____ , to fulfill all righteousness; should we not all have the need to be baptized by water also? ",
    "answer": "Water"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord has shown unto the children of men that, according to the flesh that he has humbled himself before the Father.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep31:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:7",
    "question": "By being baptized; the Lord witnessed unto the Father that he would be obedient unto him in keeping his _____.",
    "answer": "Commandments"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:8",
    "question": "What kind of form of bird descended upon Jesus Christ after he was baptized, as the Holy Ghost?",
    "answer": "Dove"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord shows unto the children of men the straightness of the path, and the narrowness of the gate, by which they should enter, he having set the example.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep31:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that the Lord has said unto the children of men to follow the devil and not him.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep31:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:11",
    "question": "And the Father said:”Repent ye, _____ ye, and be baptized in the name of my Beloved Son”.",
    "answer": "Repent"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:11, 2Nep2:28",
    "question": "Other names that we can use to describe Jesus Christ are:  The Messiah, Holy One of Israel, Mediator, and the _____ Son. ",
    "answer": "Beloved"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:12",
    "question": "Be baptized in my name, to him will the _____ give the Holy Ghost, like unto me.",
    "answer": "Father"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:12",
    "question": "The Lord has said:  Follow me, and do the things which ye have seen me _____.",
    "answer": "Do"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:13",
    "question": "We should follow the Son, with a full purpose of heart, repenting of our sins, witnessing unto the Father that we are willing to take upon the name of _____.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:13",
    "question": "After we are baptized with water, we shall receive the Holy Ghost; yea, then comes the baptism of _____ and of the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "Fire"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When we are baptized by water and have received the baptism of fire and of the Holy Ghost, we should not deny Jesus Christ, and if we do, it is better that we should have not known him.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep31:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi heard God say:”Yea, the words of my Beloved are true and faithful, and he that endures to the end shall be saved”.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep31:15"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi said that unless a man shall endure to the end, in following the example of the Son of the living God, he cannot be _____. (a) made clean (b) saved or (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep31:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:17",
    "question": "Nephi was shown by God the _____ by which we should enter the Kingdom of Heaven.",
    "answer": "Gate"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:17",
    "question": "The gate by which we should enter is repentance and baptism by water; and then comes a _____ of our sins by fire and by the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "Remission"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "After we do all the things which God has commanded, we are in the straight and narrow path which leads to _____ life.  (a) eternal (b) a better or (c) hum, hum-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep31:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "After we are in the straight and narrow path of the Lord; we our finished with all that we can do.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep31:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "We are thus far saved by the word of Christ with unshaken faith in him, relying wholly upon the merits of him who is mighty to save.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep31:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Wherefore ye should press forward with a _____ in Christ, having perfect brightness of hope, and of love of God and of all men.  (a) steadfastness (b) word or (c) neither a nor b-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep31:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:20",
    "question": "Wherefore, if ye shall press forward_____ upon the words of Christ, and endure to the end, behold, thus saith the Father:  Ye shall have eternal life.",
    "answer": "Feasting"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:21",
    "question": "Behold, there is none other way or name given under heaven whereby man can be _____ in the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Saved"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep31:21",
    "question": "The doctrine of Christ; is the one and only true doctrine of the _____, and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "Father"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:2",
    "question": "After we receive the Holy Ghost, Nephi said that we can speak with the _____ of angels only by and through the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "Tongue"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Angels speak by the power of the Holy Ghost.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep32:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:3",
    "question": "Wherefore, I said unto you, feast upon the words of Christ; for behold, the words of Christ will tell you all _____ what you should do.",
    "answer": "Things"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:4",
    "question": "It we cannot understand the word of Christ, it is because we do not ask, neither do we knock, wherefore, we are not brought into the light, but must perish in the _____.",
    "answer": "Dark"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "For behold, again I say unto you that if ye will enter in by the way, and receive the Holy Ghost, it will show unto you all the things which ye should do. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep32:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Behold, this is the doctrine of Christ, and there will be no more doctrine given until after he shall manifest himself unto you in the _____.  (a) flesh (b) day or (c) neither a nor b-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep32:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "After the Lord shall manifest himself in the flesh, and unto the Nephites, the things which he shall say unto you shall ye observe to do.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep32:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:7",
    "question": "Nephi could not say more concerning the doctrine of Christ because the _____ stopped his utterance.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi mourned because of the stiffneckedness, unbelief, and wickedness of men.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep32:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote and said that the Lord has given to us the doctrine of Christ in plainness, even as plain as word could be.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep32:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:8",
    "question": "For if we hearken unto the _____, it teaches man to pray.",
    "answer": "Spirit"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that the spirit of the devil also teaches that men must pray unto God.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep32:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "But behold, I say unto you that ye must pray always, and not _____.  (a) faint (b) during Monday Night Football or (c) during the Super Bowl-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep32:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:9",
    "question": "We must not perform any thing unto the Lord save in the first place we should pray unto the Father in the name of _____.",
    "answer": ["savior", "lord", "christ"]
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep32:9",
    "question": "We pray unto the father in the name of Christ that he may consecrate our performance unto ourselves, and that it will be for the welfare of our _____.",
    "answer": "Souls- "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi confessed to us that he was mighty in writing as well as speaking.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi could not write all the things that were taught to the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:1",
    "question": "When a man speaks by the power of the Holy Ghost the power of the Holy Ghost carries it unto the _____ of the children of men.",
    "answer": "Hearts"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "But behold, there are many that harden their hearts against the Holy Spirit, that it has no place in them.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "There are many people that cast away the things which are written and esteem them as things of no great worth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi esteemed the words that he wrote as of great worth, especially unto the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi did not pray very much for his people, because they were beyond forgiveness.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:3",
    "question": "Nephi’s eyes watered his _____ by night, because of the great concern he had for his people.",
    "answer": "Pillow"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi cried unto the Lord in faith, and he knew that Heavenly Father would hear his cries.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi testified that the Lord would not consecrate his prayers for the gain of his people. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:4",
    "question": "Nephi said that the words that he had written in_____ would be made strong unto his people.",
    "answer": "Weakness"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The words of Nephi will persuade the Nephites to do Good. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi’s words made the people of Nephi know concerning their _____.  (a) color (b) fathers or (c) goodness-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep33:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi testified that his words spoke of Jesus Christ and persuaded his people to believe in him, and endure to the end.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "We do not have to endure to the end to have eternal life.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s words speak harshly against sin, according the plainness of the truth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:5",
    "question": "  The people that will be angry with the words that Nephi has written will be those that have the spirit of the _____.",
    "answer": ["devil", "satan"]
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi gloried in plainness, in truth, and in Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:6",
    "question": "Who has redeemed Nephi’s soul from the depths of hell?",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi had _____ for his people, and great faith in Jesus Christ.  (a) hope (b) faith or (c) charity-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep33:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:8",
    "question": "Nephi had charity for the “_____-I say Jew, because I mean them from whence I came”.",
    "answer": "Jew"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi had great faith in Jesus Christ and believed that he would meet many of us spotless before the judgment seat of Christ.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:9",
    "question": "Nephi also had charity for the Gentiles but said that they should be reconciled unto _____, and enter the narrow gate and walk in to the straight path that leads to eternal life.",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "We must continue in the straight path that leads to eternal life until all the days of our probation.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi wrote to his beloved brethren, and also the Jew, and to all the ends of the _____.  (a) time (b) earth or (c) universe-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep33:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that we should hearken unto his words and believe in Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi wrote that if we do not believe in his words, at least we should believe in Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said that if we would not believe in Jesus Christ, we would not believe in the words that he had written.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:10",
    "question": "Whose words are the words that Nephi has written?",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:10",
    "question": "Who gave Nephi the words that he should write and teach all men that they should do good?",
    "answer": ["savior", "lord", "jesus", "christ"]
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "We should not judge the words of Jesus Christ; for if we do, he will show us with power and great _____, that they are his at the last day.  (a) force (b) glory or (c) intention-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep33:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": " Nephi and us will stand face to face before the judgment bar of Jesus Christ?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "We will not all see Nephi in the last day, before the judgment seat of Jesus Christ. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was not commanded by Jesus Christ or anyone else to write the words he wrote.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi had weakness in his knees when he wrote the words that he was commanded to write by Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi prayed unto the Father in the name of Jesus Christ that many of us, if not all, would be saved.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "2Nep33:12",
    "question": "In what kingdom did Nephi wanted us to be saved in the last day?",
    "answer": ["father", "christ"]
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi spoke to us as the voice of one _____, from the dust.  (a) yelling (b) begging or (c) crying-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep33:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi wrote unto us and said _____, until that great day shall come.  (a) good-bye (b) farewell or (c) adieu-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "2Nep33:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi said farewell to those that would not partake in the goodness of God, and not respect the words of the Jews, and also his words.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "2Nep33:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi words and other people’s words; will not condemn us at the last day.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:14"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi was commanded by the Lord to seal on earth all things or words that will be brought against us at the judgment bar of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi’s last four words to us were:  I must obey.  Amen ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 2Nep33:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "When the Book of Jacob begins; how many years had passed away since Lehi and his party left Jerusalem.  (a) 25 (b) 55 or (c) 75-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac1:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "How many chapters are there in the Book of Jacob? (a) 5 (b) 6 or (c) 7-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob was commanded by the Lord to write the words which he wrote in what is now known to us as- the Book of Jacob.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac1:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "On what size of plates did Jacob write the things which he was commanded by Nephi? (a) large (b) small or (c) very small-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac1:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob wrote upon the plates a _____ of the things which he considered to be most precious.  (a) a lot (b) few or (c) bunch-(B) Jac",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "1:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob was not to touch, save it were lightly, concerning the history of the people of Nephi.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The history of Jacob’s people should be engraved on other plates.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said that the history of his people would be engraved on more than one set of plates.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:3",
    "question": "Jacob was commanded by Nephi to preserve these plates and hand them down unto his seed, from generation to _____.",
    "answer": "Generation"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob was to engrave the heads of them upon the plates, if they were preaching which was sacred, or revelation which was great, or prophesying.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob was to touch or write upon the plates as much as it was possible, for ____ sake, and for the sake of his people.  (a) his (b) Christ’s or (c) the devils- (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:5",
    "question": "Because of _____ and great anxiety, it truly had been made manifest unto Jacob’s people, what things should happen to them.",
    "answer": "Faith"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob and his people had many revelations, and the spirit of much _____.  (a) thinking (b) prophecy or (c) foolishness-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac1:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of revelation and much prophecy, Jacob and his people knew of Jesus Christ; and his kingdom which should come.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac:17",
    "question": "Wherefore Jacob labored _____ among his people to persuade them to come to Christ and partake of his goodness.",
    "answer": "Diligently"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wanted to persuade all men not to rebel against God, and provoke him to get angry.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "God does not get angry with the children of men.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac1:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob hoped that all men would believe in Christ, and view his death, and suffer his cross and bear the shame of the world.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob took it upon himself to fulfill the _____ of his brother Nephi.  (a) commandment (b) words or (c) record-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac1:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob was older than his large and stature brother Nephi, by six years.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " 2Nep5:6, 1Nep2:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi anointed a man to be a king and ruler of his people, according to the reigns of kings.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Nephites loved Nephi _____.  (a) truly (b) exceedingly or (c) so and so- (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac1:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:10",
    "question": "Nephi had been a great protector of the Nephites and had wielded the sword of _____ in their defense.",
    "answer": "Laban"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Nephi did not labor very much in his days with the Nephites for their welfare.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac1:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Nephites wanted to honor and retain in remembrance his name, so whoever reigned in his stead was called 2nd Nephi, 3rd Nephi, and so forth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "When Nephi died, the words that were spoken during his funeral are written down for us to read and remember.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac1:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "There were many people during Jacob’s day and that put the suffix-ites, according to the name of their Leaders.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob would not distinguish some of the different tribes or people by their names of their leaders.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said that those that were friendly toward the Nephites’, or the people of Nephi were Nephites. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that those that seeked to destroy the Nephites were called Lamanites, according to the reigns of the kings.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In what reign of king did the Nephites begin to grow hard in their hearts, and indulge themselves somewhat in wicked practices.  (a) 2nd  (b) 3rd or (c) 4th- (A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac1:15"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:15",
    "question": "Jacob compared the Nephites practices like of King David of old, desiring many wives and _____.",
    "answer": "Concubines"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:15",
    "question": "Jacob mentioned what son of King David of the bible in his writings.",
    "answer": "Solomon"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Nephites began to search for much gold, and silver, and be lifted up somewhat in their pride.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:17",
    "question": "Jacob taught the Nephites the words that were taught to him in the _____ by the Lord.",
    "answer": "Temple"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:18, 2Nep5:6",
    "question": "Jacob and his younger brother _____ were consecrated priests and teachers by the hand of Nephi.",
    "answer": "Joseph"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob and Joseph did not magnify their offices or callings unto the Lord.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac1:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob and Joseph took upon the responsibility, answering the sins of the people upon their heads if they did not teach them the word of God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "If Jacob and Joseph did not labor diligently, the blood of the Nephites would come upon their garments on judgment day.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "Jac1:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "It is safe to assume that Jacob and Joseph will be found spotless at the last day.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " 1Jac:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob did not magnify his office with soberness as he ought to have had: As to rid his garments of the Nephites sins.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac2:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob declared the word of God unto the Nephites in a _____.  (a) church (b) temple or (c) salt box-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:3",
    "question": "Jacob was weighed down with much desire and anxiety for the welfare of the Nephites _____.",
    "answer": "Souls-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob did not refer to Jesus Christ as the Creator.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac2:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Nephites were beginning to labor in sin, which appeared very abominable unto him and unto God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:6",
    "question": "Because of the sins of the Nephites- it grieved Jacob’s soul, and caused him to shrink before his _____. ",
    "answer": "Maker-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob testified before his Maker, concerning the wickedness of the hearts of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:7",
    "question": "It grieved Jacob that he had to use so much boldness of speech concerning the Nephites, before their _____ and their children.",
    "answer": "Wives-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The feelings of the Nephites wives and children were exceedingly tender and chaste and delicate before God, which thing is pleasing unto God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:8",
    "question": "The pleasing _____ or words of God could heal the wounded soul of the Nephites and can also be applied unto us.",
    "answer": "Word-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob was given a _____ commandment by God to admonish the Nephites according to their crimes and to enlarge the wounds of those who they have already wounded.  (a) strict (b) lesser or (c) neither a nor b-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob was told to say other words by God, instead of consoling and healing those that had been wounded.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob said that the Nephites had placed _____ to pierce their souls and wound their delicate minds in those that they had already wounded.  (a) knives (b) daggers or (c) swords-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob was to tell his people concerning their wickedness, and _____, in the presence of the pure in heart, and the broken heart.  (a) looks (b) doings or (c) abominations-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "According to Jacob, the Almighty God has a piercing eye and can see us in a glance.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:11",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites the truth according to the plainness of the word of _____.",
    "answer": "God-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob would never inquire of the Lord, and instead, relied upon his own wisdom and understanding.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac2:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac1:11",
    "question": "Jacob was told by the Lord to go up into the _____, and declare the word which I will give thee unto this people.",
    "answer": "Temple-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:12",
    "question": "Jacob said that the land of promise had _____, silver, and all manner of precious ores.",
    "answer": "Gold-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Some of the Nephites had obtained more abundantly than their brethren, and were lifted up in the pride of their hearts.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac1:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:13",
    "question": "Some of the Nephites would wear stiff necks and high heads because of the costliness of their _____.",
    "answer": "Apparel-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that some of the Nephites would persecute their brethren because some had more worldly things than others.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:14",
    "question": "But he has condemned you, and if you persist in your evil ways his judgments must _____ come unto you.",
    "answer": "Speedily-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob wished the Lord would show the Nephites that he could pierce them with the glance of his eye and smite them to the _____! (a) sky (b) kingdom come or (c) dust-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:15"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:16",
    "question": "Jacob wanted his people to get rid of their iniquities and _____.",
    "answer": "Abominations-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "O that you would listen unto the word of his commands and not let this _____ of your hearts destroy your souls!  (a) lust (b) pride or (b) harlot-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wanted his brethren to familiarize themselves to everyone else and to free themselves of their substance.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:18",
    "question": "But before ye seek for _____, seek ye; for the kingdom of God.",
    "answer": "Riches- "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:19",
    "question": "And after you have obtained a _____ in Christ you shall obtain riches.",
    "answer": "Hope-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "After we obtained riches, we should clothe the naked, feed the hungry, and administer relief to the sick and the _____.  (a) poorest of the poor (b) afflicted or (c) broken heart-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord esteems or thinks some people are better than others.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac2:21"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord told Jacob that all the flesh, are of the dust.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:21"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord did not create men to keep his commandments and glorify him forever.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac2:21"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob’s heart would rejoice exceedingly because of the things the Nephites were doing.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac2:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The word of God burdens Jacob because he had to speak to the Nephites concerning their _____ crimes.  (a) grosser (b) hateful or (c) war-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:23",
    "question": "The Nephites began to _____ in iniquity; and they did not understand the scriptures, and they seeked to excuse themselves of committing whoredoms.",
    "answer": "Wax-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the things written about David, and Solomon his son, the Nephites did not understand the scriptures.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Behold, David and Solomon truly had many wives and concubines, and it was an abominable thing before the sight of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord did not lead the people out of Jerusalem, so that he could rise up a righteous branch out of the loins of Joseph.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac2:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord would not suffer that the Nephites would do the same things as those of ancient times.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob wanted the _____ to hearken unto the words of the Lord; and have one wife and no concubines.  (a) Lamanites (b) Nephites or (c) Ishmaelites-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:28",
    "question": "“For I, the Lord God, delight in the _____ of women”.",
    "answer": "Chastity-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Whoredoms are an; _____ before me; thus saith the Lord of Host.  (a) ugly (b) atrocity or (c) abomination-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:28"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord said that if the Nephites did not keep his commandments, he would curse the land for their sakes.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:29"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord did not see the sorrow, neither the mourning of the daughters of his people in the lands of Jerusalem and elsewhere.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac2:31"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "I will not suffer that the cries of the fair daughters of Jerusalem; shall come up unto me against the men of my people, saith the Lord of Hosts.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:32"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord said that the Nephites should lead away in captivity the daughters of his people because of their tenderness.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac2:33"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:34",
    "question": "And now behold, my brethren, ye know that these commandments were given to our father, _____.",
    "answer": "Lehi-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac2:35",
    "question": "Jacob said that the Nephites had done greater iniquities than their brethren, the _____.",
    "answer": "Lamanites-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Nephites had broken the heart of their tender wives, and lost the confidence of their _____.  (a) Lord (b) children or (c) horses-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:35"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the bad example before their children, the soberness of their hearts ascended up to God against them.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:35"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob wrote:  Because of the strictness of the word of God, many hearts of women died, pierced with deep _____. (a) wounds (b) daggers or (c) swords- (A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac2:35"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob taught humility and morality in chapter two, in his writings or book.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac2:1-35"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:1",
    "question": "Jacob said that he would speak to those that are pure in _____.",
    "answer": "Heart-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob said to look unto God with a firmness of _____, and pray unto him with exceeding faith.  (a) belief (b) mind or (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac3:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites that if they would pray, God would plead their cause and send down justice upon those that seek to destroy them.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac3:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "All you that are pure in heart; lift up your _____ and receive the pleasing word of God.  (a) heads (b) swords or (C) arms-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac3:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said: “Woe, Woe, Woe, unto those that are pure in heart; that are filthy this day before God”.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac3:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:3",
    "question": "What tribe of people, are cursed with a sore cursing and shall scourge the Nephites even unto destruction?",
    "answer": "Lamanites-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And the time speedily comes that the Lord will lead away the righteous from among the Nephites.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac3:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:5",
    "question": "The Nephites hated the _____ because of their filthiness and the cursing which had come upon their skin.",
    "answer": "Lamanites-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:5",
    "question": "At the time that Jacob wrote the words in chapter three of his book; the Lamanites were more righteous than the _____.",
    "answer": "Nephites-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lamanites were more righteous than the Nephites because they observed to keep the commandments of the Lord by having one wife and no concubines.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac3:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lamanites or a seed of them will become a blessed people in the last days.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac3:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob wrote: Their husbands love their wives, and their wives love their husbands; and their husbands and their wives love their _____.  (a) gold (b) platinum or (c) children-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac3:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lamanites unbelief and hatred towards the Nephites was because the iniquity of their fathers.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac3:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob asked the Nephites:  How much better are you than they, in the sight of your great Creator?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac3:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob feared that the skin of the Lamanites would be whiter than that of the Nephites, when they would be brought with them before the throne of God. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac3:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob did never, mentioned God having a throne of any kind.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac3:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:9",
    "question": "Jacob reminded the Nephites to look upon their own filthiness and to remember that the filthiness of the_____ came because or their fathers.",
    "answer": "Lamanites-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob told the Nephites to remember their children and how much grief they had brought upon them, because of their bad examples.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac3:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "It was the Nephites strength and power that would bring their children unto destruction.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac3:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "O my brethren, hearken unto my word; arouse the _____ of your soul; shake yourselves that ye may awake from the slumber of death.  (a) faculties (b) body (c) frame-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac3:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "If we are to loose ourselves from the chains of hell, we will become angels of the devil.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac3:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:11",
    "question": "If we are cast into the lake of fire and brimstone, we will receive what is called a _____ death.  Second ",
    "answer": "-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The lake of fire and brimstone is also called a second death by Jacob.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac3:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob spoke to the Nephites concerning _____ and lasciviousness, and every other kind of sin.  (a) adultery (b) fornication or (c) marriage-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac3:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob did not tell the Nephites concerning their sins and the awful consequences of them.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac3:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "A _____ part of the proceedings of the Nephites cannot be written upon the plates that Jacob was talking about.  (a) thousand (b) hundredth or (c) million- (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac3:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Many of the proceedings of the Nephites are written on much smaller plates.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac3:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:13",
    "question": "The large plates of the Nephites contain their wars, and contentions, and the _____ of their kings.",
    "answer": "Reigns-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The plates that contain the words of Jacob; are called the plates of Jacob.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac3:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac3:14",
    "question": "By whose hand were the plates of Jacob made? ",
    "answer": "Nephi-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob could not make his own plates because he _____.  (a) had arthritis (b) did not know how or (c) we don’t know why-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac3:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob did not minister the words of Christ unto his people.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac4:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob could not write but a little of his words upon the plates because of the difficulty in engraving.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob knew nevertheless, that the things which he and Nephi wrote upon the plates would one day be erased or destroyed.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac4:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that he and Nephi could write on other things besides the plates and they would not perish or vanish.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac4:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": " Because the Lord would protect their writings; Jacob knew that they could write upon plates of Brass.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi wrote in order to give their children, and beloved brethren, a small degree of knowledge concerning them and their fathers.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob labored diligently to engrave words on the plates in order that their children and their brethren, world receive them with thankful _____.  (a) souls (b) hearts or (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac4:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi wanted their brethren to look upon the plates and learn with joy and not sorrow, neither with contempt, concerning their last parents.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac4:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:4",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob wrote with the intent that their brethren would know that they knew of _____.",
    "answer": "Christ-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Nephi and Jacob knew of Jesus Christ and had a hope of his glory a _____ years before his coming.  (a) 1,000 (b) 200 or (c) 100-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac4:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The holy prophets also had a hope of Jesus Christ and his glory, even those that came before Nephi and Jacob and testified before his actual coming.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:5",
    "question": "The holy prophets believed in Christ and worshiped the _____ in his name, and also Jacob and Nephi worshiped the Father in his name.",
    "answer": "Father-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The intent that Jacob and his people kept the Law of Moses; was that it would point their souls to the Lord.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob only mentioned Abraham the father of Isaac, once in the Book of Mormon. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:5",
    "question": "When Abraham offered Isaac unto God, it was a similitude of God and his Only_____ Son.",
    "answer": "Begotten-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "We search the prophets, and have the many revelations and the spirit of prophecy; we obtain a hope and our faith becomes unshaken.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:6",
    "question": "Jacob and Nephi wrote that they can command in the name of _____; and the very trees obey us, or the mountains, or the waves of the sea.",
    "answer": "Jesus-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wrote: nevertheless, the Lord God shows us our weakness that we may know that it is by his grace and his great condescensions, that they have power to do these things.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said that the Lord’s works were no big deal and not very marvelous.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac4:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that it is impossible for man to know all the mysterious and the ways of our Heavenly Father.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "And no man knows the ways of the Lord, except it be revealed unto him.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren not to despise the _____ of God.  (a) things (b) revelations or (c) glory-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac4:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that by the power of God’s word, man came upon the face of the earth.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren to seek not to _____ the Lord, but to take counsel from his hand.  (a) question (b) criticize or (c) counsel-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac4:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:10",
    "question": "God counsels in _____, and in justice, and in great mercy, over all his works.",
    "answer": "Wisdom-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:11",
    "question": "Jacob told us to be _____ unto God through the atonement of Christ, his Only Begotten Son, and ye may obtain a resurrection.",
    "answer": "Reconciled-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob told his brethren to marvel at the things that he had spoken to them, and not to publicly speak of the atonement of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac4:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "According to Jacob, the Spirit speaks the truth and lies when it only benefits us.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac4:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Wherefore, the Spirit speaks of things as they really are, and of things as they really will be, wherefore, these things are manifested plainly unto us.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said that we ourselves, are the only witnesses to and of the things the Spirit tells us.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac4:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:13",
    "question": "God is also a witness to the things the Spirit witnesses to us and also are his _____.",
    "answer": "Prophets-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "But behold, the _____ were a stiffnecked people, and they despised the words of plainness.",
    "answer": "Jews-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:14",
    "question": "Who killed the prophets, and sought for things they could not understand?",
    "answer": "Jews-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Wherefore because of their blindness, which blindness came by looking beyond the _____.   (a) truth (b) mark or (c) point-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac4:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Jews must fall, because they were looking beyond the mark.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Why did God take away his plainness from the Jews, and delivered unto them many things which they could not understand? (a) they deserved it (b) they desired it or (c) we don’t know-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac4:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Jews stumbled because of the things they desired and the Lord has done it.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who led Jacob to prophesy of things to his brothers? (a) Nephi (b) Lehi or (c) the Spirit-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac4:15"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac4:15",
    "question": "Jacob prophesied that by the stumbling of the _____ they will reject the very stone upon which they might build and have a safe foundation.",
    "answer": "Jews-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "According to the _____ this stone shall become the great, and the last, and the only foundation, upon which the Jews can build.  (a) scriptures (b) prophets or (c) The Koran-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac4:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said that it is possible for the Jews to build a foundation on the stone even after they have rejected it.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac4:17 & Jac5:50-77"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What prophet of old did Jacob refer to in Chapter 5 concerning the allegory of the tame and wild olive tree? (a) Zenock (b) Zenos or (c) Zeniff-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac5:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "An allegory is the expression by means of symbolic fictional figures and actions of truths or generalizations about human existence.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Look at your dictionary"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In what part of the vineyard did the Lord and the servant look to see if the natural branches of the tree which they had planted had brought forth much fruit.  (a) southernmost (b) nethermost or (c) northernmost-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac5:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The nethermost part of the vineyard was the poorest spot in all the land of the vineyard.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac5:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord told the servant not to question him or counsel him on the spot that he had chosen for the tree. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac5:21"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord did not know that it was the poorest place in the vineyard to plant the olive tree.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac5:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because the Lord had nourished the tree for a long time, it had brought much fruit.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "  Jac5:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord asked the servant what he could have done more for his vineyard.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac5:49"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The servant told the Lord of the vineyard to do what to the tree to bring more good fruit.  (a) cut it and start again (b) spare it a little longer or (c) to forget about it because it was useless-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac5:50"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Why did the Lord of the vineyard pluck the ripened branches from the tree? (a) because they smelled bad (b) hoped the roots may take strength because of their goodness or (c) we don’t know-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac5:59"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the changes the Lord of the vineyard had done to the branches of the olive tree; he hoped that good may overcome the evil.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac5:59"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac5:61",
    "question": "The Lord of the vineyard told his servant go to, and call servants, that we may labor _____ with our might in the vineyard.",
    "answer": "Diligently-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "If we labor with our might in the vineyard of the Lord, he has said that we shall have joy in the fruit which he shall lay up unto himself.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac5:71"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The natural fruit of the vineyard of the Lord is the most _____ unto him from the beginning.  (a) desirable (b) precious or (c) most worthy-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac5:74"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac5:75",
    "question": "Who was the Lord of the vineyard referring to when he said “Blessed art thou; for because you have been diligent in laboring with me in the vineyard”?",
    "answer": "Servants-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "There will come a time when the evil fruit shall come again into the vineyard of the Lord.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "Jac5:77"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac5:77",
    "question": "In the end; the Lord of the vineyard will cause that both the good and the _____ fruit shall be gathered; and the good will he preserve unto himself.",
    "answer": "Bad- "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What will happen to the Lord’s vineyard in the end? (a) be burned with fire (b) will become flooded or (c) be bombed by jets-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac5:77"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In the allegory of the olive-tree, what prophet spoke concerning the house of Israel in which he likened them unto a tame olive-tree that must surely come to pass? (a) Zenock (b) Zenos or (c) Zeniff-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In the last time-Who shall go forth in his power to nourish and prune his vineyard?  (a) Muslims (b) his servants or (c) migrant workers-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "After his servants prune his vineyard; the end soon comes.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac6:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Those that have labored diligently in his vineyard will not be blessed? ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac6:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "_____ are they who shall be cast out into their own place!  (a) damned (b) perish or (c) cursed-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The world in the last day will be burned by fire.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac6:2-3"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "And how _____ is our God unto us, for he has remembered the house of Israel.  (a) merciful (b) thoughtful or (c) diligent-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac6:4",
    "question": "The Lord our God has also remembered both _____ and branches of the house of Israel.",
    "answer": "Roots-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "God _____ forth his hand unto all his people all day long.  (a) extends (b) stretches or (c) gives-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who did Jacob say were gainsaying and stiffnecked people?  (a) Lamanites (b) those of the house of Israel or (c)  a and b-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:4 "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Those that harden their hearts shall be saved in the kingdom of God?",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac6:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob beseech to us in words of soberness that we would _____.  (a) believe his words (b) repent or (c) not go to hell-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wants us to come with a full purpose of heart and cleave unto God. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac6:5 "
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said that God “cleaves” unto us.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac6:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "We should cleave unto our______ while we are in this mortal life  (a) God (b) our riches or (c) our faith-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "We should not harden our hearts when the arm of mercy from the Lord is extended to us.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac6:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob said, “For behold, after you have been _____ by the good word of God all day long”.  (a) bless (b) nourished or (c) astonished-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "If we bring forth evil fruit, we must be hewn down and cast into the fire.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac6:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said the Nephites did not know that the power of the redemption and the resurrection, which is in Christ.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac6:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "According to the power of Justice, the power of the redemption and resurrection which is in Christ can be denied.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac6:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who or what has flames that are unquenchable? (a) the lake of fire and brimstone (b) an atomic blast or (c) neither a nor b-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac6:10",
    "question": "What did Jacob say is another name for endless torment?",
    "answer": "brimstone-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What gate did Jacob want us to enter?  (a) pearly gates (b) the strait and narrow or (c) the long and winding gate-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wanted us to enter the strait and narrow gate until we shall obtain eternal life.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac6:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In Jacob chapter six; Jacob said- “O be wise; what can I say more”.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac6:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob bid us farewell until we shall meet him before the pleasing bar of God.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac6:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What thing or bar “strikes the wicked with awful dread and fear”.   (a) #10 rebar (b) snickers bar or (c) pleasing bar of God-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac6:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:1",
    "question": "Who is considered, by many Book of Mormon scholars; to be the first anti-Christ mentioned in the Book of Mormon?",
    "answer": "Sharem-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In the beginning of chapter 7 what did Sharem do or say to the people of Nephi? (a) Christ had already came (b) there should be no Christ or (c) Jesus is not the Messiah-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:1 "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem did not flatter many Nephites with his flattering words.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Sharem was trying to do what with his flattering words?  (a)  say that God loves all people  (b) say that he was the Messiah or (c) overthrow the doctrine of Christ-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:2"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem labor diligently that he might lead away the hearts of the people.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "  Jac7:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Even though Shem used many flattering words; he did not lead away or astray many of the Nephites.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem did not know that Jacob had faith in Christ.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In chapter #7; who did Jacob have faith in?  (a) his own wisdom (b) in Christ or (c) the words of Plato-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:3"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who sought much opportunity that he might come unto Jacob?  (a) Moroni (b) Lehi or (c) Sharem-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem was not very wise or learned individual?",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Sharem had a_____ knowledge of the language of the Nephites.  (a)  so and so (b) perfect or (c) better-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Because of Sharem’s knowledge of the language of the Nephites he used much _____.  (a) flattery (b) wisdom or (c) understanding-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem had much power in his oratory or speech.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who gave Sharem the power of his speech?  (a) Jesus Christ (b) God or (c)  the devil or satan-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Sharem had hoped to shake Jacob of his _____.  (a) Status (b) faith or (c) wisdom-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob had seen many revelations concerning the doctrine of Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What had Jacob seen that ministered unto him?  (a) demons (b) angels or (c) UFO’s-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Whose voice had Jacob heard from time to time?  (a) his own  (b) the Lord’s or (c) Satan’s-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:5"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because of the voice Jacob had heard; he could not be shaken from his faith, by the evil Sharem. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:5"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "When Sharem first saw Jacob; he called him-(a) hey dude (b) Brother Jacob or (c) Jacob-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:6"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem had not sought much opportunity to speak with Jacob.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem accused Jacob of preaching the gospel or the doctrine of Christ?",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:6"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Sharem accused Jacob of leading away many of the Nephites unto perverting the right way of _____.  (a) Satan (b) God or (c) the world-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What law did Sharem say was the “right way”?  (a) law of physics (b) law of Moses (c) the Articles of Faith-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem said that Moses or the “Law of Moses” had already come to pass.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem tries to confuse Jacob or us by first saying that the Law of Moses is the right way, then saying that no man knows of the things to come.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In chapter #7, Sharem accuses Jacob of being a_____.  (a) false prophet (b) blasphemy or (c) we don’t know what-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob did not write unto us the matter of which Sharem contended with him.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:7"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord God poured his _____ into Jacob’s soul.  (a) thoughts (b) words or (c) Spirit-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because the Lord had poured his Spirit unto Jacob; he confounded Sharem in all his words.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": "  Jac7:8"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob said to Sharem: “Denies thou the _____ who should come'?  (a) 3 days of darkness (b) Hailey’s comet or (c) Christ-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem said that if there would be a Christ, he would deny him or his existence.",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:9",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob who said: “There is no Christ, neither has been, nor ever will be”?",
    "answer": "Sharem-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem told Jacob the he believed the scriptures.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob; what did Jacob ask Sharem if he believed in what?  (a) Einstein’s theory of relativity (b) the scriptures or (c) the Book of Mormon-  (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said that Sharem did not understand the scriptures.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:11",
    "question": "Who did Jacob say the scriptures testify of?",
    "answer": "Christ"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who did Jacob say had written and testified concerning Jesus Christ? (a) Satan (b) the Mormon’s or (c) the prophets-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:11"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "ref": "Jac7:12",
    "question": "Jacob had seen and heard the things concerning Jesus Christ.",
    "answer": "T"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "By who or what power did the things concerning Jesus Christ been manifested to Jacob?  (a) Jesus Christ (b) God or (c) the Holy Ghost-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:12",
    "question": "Jacob said that if there should be no _____ made, all mankind would be lost.  ",
    "answer": "Atonement-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem asked Jacob to show him a sign of Jesus Christ.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:13",
    "question": "Sharem accused Jacob of knowing much about this personage?   ",
    "answer": "Ghost- "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said that he would not tempt God because Sharem knew that God did really exist.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob knew that if he would show Sherem a sign that Jesus Christ did really exist, he would still deny it.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob; Who said the words? “Art of the Devil”?  ",
    "answer": "Jacob "
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said told Sharem that thy will would be done. ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "If God would smite Sharem, it would be a sign that he has great power?  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:14",
    "question": "Jacob said that God has great power both in _____ and in earth.  ",
    "answer": "Heaven-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said that Christ shall come, and that his will would be done.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Because Jacob spoke of many things concerning Jesus Christ; the power of the Lord came upon whom?  (a) Jacob (b) Sharem or (c) The devil-(B) Sharem",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:15",
    "question": "In the Book of Jacob who fell to the earth because of the Lord’s great power? ",
    "answer": "Sharem-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:15",
    "question": "In the end of the Book of Jacob who was nourished of the power of Jesus Christ for many days.  ",
    "answer": "Sharem-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Sharem was nourished of the power of Jesus Christ for ____.  (a) two days (b) many days or (c) three days-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:15"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Who told the people to gather together because he wanted to speak to them before he died?  (a) Jacob (b) Ishmael or (c) Sharem-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:16"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem the Anti-Christ knew the exact day that he would die.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:16"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because Sharem did not speak very plainly to the Nephites, they could not understand him very well.  ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In the end, Sharem denied the things that he had taught the _____.  (a) Nephites (b) Lamanites or (c) Zoramites-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Finally, in his last days, Sharem confessed of the existence of Jesus Christ.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Sharem confessed of the _____ of the Holy Ghost in the end. (a) reality (b) power or (c) existence-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:17"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem did not believe in the ministering of angels.  ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:17"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:18",
    "question": "Sharem was deceived by the power of whom? ",
    "answer": "Satan- "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Sharem spoke of _____, and of eternity, and of eternal punishment.  (a) hell (b) Nephi or (c) neither a nor b-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:18"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem felt that he had committed an unpardonable sin.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:19"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Sharem said that he had lied unto God; and denied the Christ.",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:19"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "When Sharem confessed of his wrongdoing he gave up the _____. (a) plates (b) ghost or (c) neither a nor b-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:20"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The multitude had witnessed the things which Sharem had spoken at the end of his life. ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:21"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob was not pleased when the power of God came onto the multitude after Sharem had spoken.  ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Jac7:22"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "7:21",
    "question": "The multitude fell to the _____ when God showed his power to the multitude.  ",
    "answer": "Earth-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:22",
    "question": "Jacob had requested of _____ to show his matchless power to the Nephites.  ",
    "answer": "God-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:22",
    "question": "At the end of chapter #7 of the Book of Jacob; God had heard whose cry and answered his prayer.  ",
    "answer": "Jacob-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What two things came to pass that was restored again among the people.  (a) freedom of speech and writing (b) peace and love God or (c) the will of agency and baptism-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:23"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:23",
    "question": "The Nephites searched the_____, and hearkened, no more to the wicked man known as Sharem.  ",
    "answer": "Scriptures-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In the end of the Book of Jacob we are told that many ways were devised to reclaim and restore the Lamanites to the truth of the Gospel.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lamanites delighted in wars and _____. (a) partying (b) whoredoms or (c) bloodshed-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:24"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:24",
    "question": "The Lamanites had an_____ hatred for their brethren, the Nephites.  ",
    "answer": "Eternal- "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:24",
    "question": "Who sought by the power of their arms to destroy the Nephites?  ",
    "answer": "Lamanites-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The people of_____ fortified their armies against the Lamanites.  (a) Nephi (b) Zoram or (c) Ishmaelites-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:25",
    "question": "What people used their might, trusting in the God and the rock of their salvation?  ",
    "answer": "Nephites-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Because the Nephites trusted in God; they became conquerors of their enemies, during Jacob’s life.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:25"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "When Jacob began to be old, he said that the record of the Nephites was kept on the other plates of _____. (a) Laban (b) Nephi or (c) Lehi-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:26"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob concluded with his record, declaring that he had written according to the best of his_____.  (a) knowledge (b) penmanship or (c) memory-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob said that his life and the lives of the Nephites had passed away like as it were a dream.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:26"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "In the end of his writings: What tribe of people did Jacob declare were wanderers?  (a) Lamanites (b) Nephites or (c) Ishmaelites-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:26"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The people of Nephi were lonesome and solemn people, cast out from what city.  (a) Salt Lake (b) Dallas or (c) Jerusalem-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob wrote that he and his people were born in tribulation, and in a wilderness.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:26"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "What thing or attitude caused wars and contentions between the Nephites and Lamanites?  (a) pride (b) hatred or (c) agency-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:26"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "In the end of the Book of Jacob, he said that he and the people of Nephi mourn out our last days.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:26"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "At the end of his life, what son of Jacob took over the plates?  ",
    "answer": "Enos "
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob was_____ when he passed away.  (a) 75 (b) 100 or (c) we don’t know- (C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "What is the name of Enos’s uncle who told Jacob of things he had commanded him to do? ",
    "answer": "Nephi-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Enos promised Jacob that he would be obedient unto his commands.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Jacob considered that his writing on the plates had been_____. (a) small (b) sufficient or (c) too much-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Jac7:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "At the end of his writing, Jacob bid us all farewell.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:27"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Jacob hoped that of his many of his brethren would read his writings.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Jac7:27"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Jac7:27",
    "question": "What is the last word that is written in the Book of Jacob? Adieu ",
    "answer": "-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:l",
    "question": "Who was Nephi’s nephew that wrote the third book in the Book of Mormon? ",
    "answer": "Enos-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "It came to pass that Enos knew that his father was a_____ man.  (a) just (b) holy or (c) unworthy-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Enos1:1"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": "Was a prophet of the Lord and also the father of Enos?  ",
    "answer": "Jacob-"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:1,27",
    "question": "How many chapters are in the book of Enos?",
    "answer": ["One", "1"]
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Enos was not taught in the language of his father, therefore he made up his own.  ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Enos1:1"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:1",
    "question": " Who taught Enos of the nurture and admonition of the Lord? ",
    "answer": "Father"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:2",
    "question": "And I will tell you of the_____ which I had before God, before I received a remission of my sins.",
    "answer": "Wrestle"
  },
  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The word wrestle is only mentioned once in the Book of Mormon.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Enos1:2"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Enos went to hunt_____ in the forest.  (a) wild game (b) bears or (c) beasts-(C)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Enos1:3"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:3",
    "question": "Enos’s father spoke to him concerning eternal_____, and the joy of the saints, and those words sank deep into his heart.  ",
    "answer": "Life-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "And my soul hungered; and I kneeled down before my_____.  (a) alter (b) Maker or (c) pile of gold-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Enos1:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Enos cried unto his Maker in mighty prayer and supplication for his own soul.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Enos1:4"
  },
  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "Enos cried unto his Maker all day long, and when the night came, he raised his voice high that it reached the_____.  (a) heavens (b) moon or (c) stars-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Enos1:4"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:5",
    "question": "Who said: “Enos, thy sins are forgiven thee, and thou shalt be blessed” ",
    "answer": "God-"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:6",
    "question": "And I, _____, knew that God could not lie; wherefore, my guilt was swept away.  ",
    "answer": "Enos-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Enos asked the Lord how it was done that his sins were forgiven.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Enos1:7"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:8",
    "question": "How was Enos’ guilt for his sins forgiven?",
    "answer": "faith"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that two years would pass away before Christ would manifest himself in the flesh.  ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Enos1:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that his faith alone did not make him whole.  ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Enos1:8"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "When Enos heard the words of the Lord he began to feel a desire, for the welfare of his brethren, the_____.  (a) Lamanites (b) Nephites or (c) Zoramites-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Enos1:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Enos poured out his whole soul unto God, for the welfare of the Nephites.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Enos1:9"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Enos struggled in the spirit while he was praying for the welfare of the Nephites.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Enos1:10"
  },
  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that he would visit his brethren according to their_____ in keeping his commandment.",
    "answer": "Diligence"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Enos was told by the Holy Ghost that the land of promise was a holy land.  ",
    "answer": "F",
    "ref": " Enos1:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord told Enos that he would curse the land of promise save it be for the cause of_____.  (a) iniquity (b) wars or (c) contentions-(A)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Enos1:10"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:10",
    "question": "Their transgressions will I bring down with sorrow upon their own_____.  ",
    "answer": "Heads-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "After Enos heard the words of the Lord, his faith began to be unshaken in the Lord.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Enos1:11"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:11",
    "question": "Enos prayed unto the Lord with many long struggles, for his brethren, the_____.  ",
    "answer": "Lamanites-"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Enos prayed and labored with all his diligence unto the Lord.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Enos1:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lord said unto Enos that he would grant his desires because of his_____.  (a) wishes (b) faith or (c) humble heart-(B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Enos1:12"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Enos desired of the Lord: That if the Nephites should fall because of transgression and the Lamanites should not be destroyed, that he would preserve the record of his people.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Enos1:13"
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:13",
    "question": "Enos desired that the record of his people be brought forth at some future day unto the_____; that they may be brought forth unto salvation.  ",
    "answer": "Lamanites- "
  },

  {
    "type": "fill",
    "ref": "Enos1:14",
    "question": "For at the present our struggles were vain in restoring Lamanites to the true_____.  ",
    "answer": "Faith-"
  },

  {
    "type": "multi",
    "question": "The Lamanites swore in their wrath that if it were possible, they would destroy the Nephites and their records, and also all the_____ of their fathers.  (a) traditions (b) customs or (c) their sign language.- (B)",
    "options": [],
    "answer": "",
    "ref": "Enos1:14"
  },

  {
    "type": "bool",
    "question": "Enos cried unto the Lord continually because he knew that he would preserve their records.  ",
    "answer": "T",
    "ref": " Enos1:15"
  }
]
